hey hello how are you welcome to
the junkyard love podcast it's me your
host
dwayne the rock johnson's stunt double
i'm happy you're here
today's episode is with ryan santos this
is his
second appearance on the podcast and i
thought i'd take the first few minutes
of this
to kind of explain where we landed in
our conversation and kind of
contrast where it where it changes and
where it differs from
maybe our first conversation and kind of
the
the mindset the mindset and the
just place where we're coming from so
the first episode was recorded before
this pandemic it was recorded
before the coronavirus the covet
situation was was a thing right but
before it had
really hit america and changed you know
with the lockdown and all the political
madness that goes with all of this
all these different changes that we've
had to experience
you know being sent in doors and being
sent
inside psychologically in many ways
it's it's it's changed how our
conversations have been framed and so
actually i wanted to kind of come on
here in in
express the importance of podcasts
because of this because of this contrast
that i noticed
listening back to this episode it's
crazy we know
as much as i try to as a host i don't
want to take
a bunch of covid talk and run run the
whole podcast
um talking about the coronavirus like i
try to
try to step us away from it where i can
or you know oh we've been talking about
too much like let's get it's here it's a
thing we're all dealing with right we're
all kind of experiencing some sort of
difference in our life um and it's it's
the first part of conversation it's
where we meet each other at
often and so it's interesting to
for this episode we we did carry on a
lot about kind of
our our personal experiences over the
last year
and uh it was actually turned into quite
a beautiful conversation around
um dealing with this craziness dealing
with these changing times dealing with
um not knowing where to get our truth
from dealing with
uh the suffering um that we're all kind
of going through but we don't really
know how to express it we don't really
know how to
to show up as our best selves we're all
really just kind of
kind of going through this rocky time um
without the ability to properly
communicate about it um you know it's
very interesting to me that you know not
just because the lockdown but because of
the things that seem to be attached to
the lockdown and the
in the the censorship and these sorts of
things
there's legitimately a chance that this
episode will be removed from youtube and
spotify
and apple music for false information
and um i mean really noticing how
crazy that is how how um
not not adhering to freedom of speech
that that really is
uh but you know it's something that
we're all kind of going through it's
something that we're all kind of
experiencing in this you know ryan opens
up his his ability to be so vulnerable
with me on this podcast is
is quite fantastic he opens up and just
kind of is expressing at some point
you know i i don't know what to say i
don't know if i'm going to get cancelled
i don't know if i'm going to get in
trouble
i don't know how to properly communicate
this i feel like we're not allowed to i
feel like
everything we say is right on the edge
of some giant argument
we don't know what news sources the
other person across the table
has been listening to we're dealing with
clashes
amongst our family members in our
communities with our friends
uh a lot of head-butting from narratives
that aren't really our narratives we're
kind of trying to explore
our lived experience and check in on the
bigger global narrative and see where we
fit in it and i think a lot of us are
finding that
we don't really know where our opinions
are and we don't know if we're like
really allowed to have our opinions
somehow
um it's a very strange time and uh i
think that
us going through this this in-depth
conversation the first hour and a half
is this is kind of where we landed just
just the weirdness of all this and
and how we don't feel as if we can
communicate
fully and we're just confused and um
you know emotional and the beauty of
this podcast is
you know i i've had a couple of these
really where
i i wanna i have my serious episodes i
have my my episodes where we talk about
childhood trauma
and when we talk about um growing out of
of
lack mindsets and and growing into fixed
mindsets and
i have motivational talks and i have um
you know episodes that i that i go into
it and i'm like we're gonna we're gonna
dive into this
self-help stuff we're going to dive into
the self-development because i really
want to just try to mind this person for
what they know
because if i can set the stage for them
to say the proper things it really will
help the listeners
and then there's also this other side of
the podcast that i
that i want to just be able to have
open bullshitting conversations really i
want to be able to have you know not
not dipping our toes in into gossip and
and talking about others but
you know even just in the casual you
know bros hanging out
shooting the [__] having a beer that
stumbles into
into awesome awesome sides of our of our
personality and of our perspective so
i i really i went into this episode i
had ryan come over to my home
um we didn't do the zoom call you know
it was like dude come over i was like
i'll get a six-pack
um you know we figured we'd just bs hang
out for hours
see where it goes uh we'd crack some
jokes we'd laugh whatever but
the again the beauty of the podcast is
it sets the stage for for like what's
really going on
you know you can't tiptoe around the
[__] you know it's
um we we end up just
opening up to each other and what you're
able to see in here as a listener
is you know you're kind of getting a
third person view a a
like a you know we put up a camera as
you're watching two
good friends um speak frankly with each
other
you're kind of getting in on this like
brotherly love
this um this vulnerability that
you know you you know it's it's not
locker room
talk it's uh it's it's kind of these
real states of
of friendship that you get to kind of
see
see in in man to me that's just so
phenomenally
phenomenally beautiful and um
and priceless really for me so
so so as a host i just i just i want to
preface this episode
and uh just say i'm so glad that it
happened the way that it did
i'm so glad like i think that we both
said
and uncovered things that will be
helpful uh for sure are helpful to
to some listeners to some people going
through similar experiences
you know as much as i want to you know i
always say uh uh
you know sometimes you got to lift up
your feet and let the river just kind of
take you down it
uh this was one of those experiences
where i'm like this is an episode we're
not gonna talk about anything serious
we're gonna just come over me and ryan
are just gonna have a few beers and get
a little buzzed
and [__] and hopefully crack a few
jokes and and that's what this episode
will be and
uh it did have that for sure we
certainly do
we we have our moments for sure and and
the whole last end is
is all is pretty fun and games but uh um
we
we ended up not being able you know i i
kind of had to lift my legs up
you know just it just inevitably we we
went to this place where it just seemed
important
to keep kind of digging in and having
that conversation with my good friend
so i'm grateful for this podcast i'm
grateful for the things that it opens up
um i i'm grateful for for vulnerability
and uh and really just the ability to to
try to to stumble our way
through this thing and uh you know just
this the the the powerful the powerful
things that uh that well you know one
conversation
with inquisitiveness and in in respect
and and love for the other person
can really help us um explore what's
what's eating us up and and explore
what's what's on our minds
and help us kind of work through it so
um
yeah i uh we'll get going with the
podcast i'm glad you guys are here
i'm glad you're listening uh i
appreciate you if you resonate with any
of this
um you know maybe send us a message or
or leave a comment or
share or you know maybe just keep it to
yourself i get that too so
if this does resonate with you and it
does speak to you
just know that you're not alone just
know that we
we're all going through some form of of
weirdness right now for sure
and none of us are claiming to have it
figured out none of us are claiming to
be the ones with all the right answers
um
but but but i think that openly speaking
about it and not being afraid to speak
about it
especially if that's something that's
coming up with these social media
platforms now
now canceling and picking what truth is
is
very very very weird time um it's an
especially very weird time to have
public conversations like this
um with with you know some some obtuse
opinions and some vulnerability
and some some honest truths so um
yeah i hope you enjoyed the episode it
is me
and ryan tose santos enjoy
knowledge is power
[Music]
yeah it uh it works i mean it's not like
i'm literally still using i'm using
imovie
for which is like dude
like the basic old and it's it's slow
like i i don't think i'm gonna
be able to use imovie for super long
like if i keep doing more of these where
i'm
uploading quite a bit of video it
doesn't it starts to lag after a bit oh
it does it really
yeah i mean my computer is built for
djing
my computer is like okay you know i mean
like like
my computer's pretty maxed out with my
like music production
in djing and stuff and throwing video on
to it is like a whole nother it's like
holy [__] dude how much are you gonna
overload me with you know my computer
starts to
kissed at me a little bit so okay yeah
because i like made like a funny
little uh
30 i don't even know if it was 30
seconds but it was like
15 seconds or something it was probably
seconds i put some background music and
it was me
uh it was like i for some reason i got
off
work early and i was like
really bored and i didn't feel like
doing anything like
i didn't feel like playing video games
or like a video game or
anything i was just like messing around
with or i was just looking at imovie
so i kind of like looked at it i'm like
okay and i and i was like not
i was basically teaching myself how to
use it i made like a 30 second like
video of me having one of my cats on my
chest
and i put this like soothing
like a commercial music in the
background
you know yeah it's almost like the the
slow mo and i put in slow motion like
the video
clip nice and i sent it to katie and
she's like
what are you even doing i'm a video
editor yeah
this was like two years ago or something
and i was like i don't know but i think
i should start making commercials it's
fun
yeah that's funny i mean like i don't
know i love commercials i love watching
them
like i will actually if it's like you
know the have you ever seen the
um the gum one i think it's
the one where like the ma or the not the
mom but the dad and the daughter
they make the paper or the origami
no i don't think i see anything they
make or like they make origami they're
like first okay
let me set the scene they're on a train
okay they're like having like a
daddy-daughter trip right they're just
hanging out and the girl is pretty young
and but this guy i don't know
what company it is i keep forgetting
what company but they make origami
right and that's their thing every time
they have this piece of gum they make
origami out of the wrapper
okay okay so and then she gets a little
bit older
you know and they're just making origami
every time they have that gum making
origami
and then later on towards the end of the
video or the commercial
this is like one of the long commercials
whatever so they
she's going away to college you know
she's leaving home she's moving they're
packing
and he's just like hey you know you can
tell it's like he's really sad about it
and she's like suit whatever and she's
like
ready to go and he is packing one of the
box she's like what the heck
you know what the heck is this box in it
he it like fell
off like out of the back of the car
and it spilled all the origami
they made since that first one wow
and after that she looked up at him
and he's like oh my god yeah i'm like
tearing up right now
i know you know because i can see it in
my head because now that you have a
child like dude
yeah i didn't even have a child the
first time i watched it i freaking cried
i was like
no and i dude i was like
freaking this was like before i met
katie yeah i think when i watched
like this is like a pretty old
commercial and yeah i do
the commercials like if it's like that
sad i will cry mm-hmm i don't know why
yeah i i get i feel like movies get me
too i i get emotional i love when
the person who has created the trailer
the movie or the
the commercial like sometimes they can
hit it just right man it's it really is
an art in itself like they can
communicate
you know in a minute 15 seconds or even
you know 35 seconds they can communicate
something very human yeah you know and
that hits us i love that
yeah it hits me every time that like
even talking i was like oh
stop ryan because you have a daughter
now hold back the tears instead
have you been making origami with your
daughter uh absolutely not i
did not have that skill and the time
today we've got youtube now we were just
talking about youtube teaching you
lately
oh youtube has taught me a lot of things
never actually this is not i don't want
to call it sad
but as a very first thing i learned off
youtube when youtube was
not just starting because it's been
around for a long time right but it was
like one of those like
still still rough i think i was like 21.
if that i think no i was like 21 22-ish
yeah so it was still like figuring out
what it wanted yeah
there was no like whatever crazy
channels or whatever you know
not what it is now but the first thing i
learned off youtube
was how to use that little tool
to roll um
a freaking a joint a joint
yeah oh like the like um
like where you put it in between the two
things and you you start rolling
yeah yeah that was the very first thing
i learned off youtube that's [__]
epic
yeah and that's what youtube was for
yeah and then the second thing was yeah
i don't look like all this like content
it's like pretty normal now but back
then it's like i couldn't believe it was
on there
on how to use that because it was that
one and my second one i remember this
because like
that i that's just how i learned how to
do it was that and then
how to roll a blunt and that was
actually the one
how i learned how was the video of tupac
rolling a blind he's like this is how
you roll a blunt
in wow 30 seconds and that's how i
learned well bro so think about like
so so two things so firstly like youtube
is still figuring out what it wanted to
be
and it's like uh like i don't think we
really even saw
the benefits of it at that time like
when youtube first came along we didn't
realize it would be like
think about how many hundreds of
thousands of hours of tutorials we can
upload or different people can upload
through across the world
that can now teach other other people
from
other sides of the world how did how to
do things like you were talking about
like you were working on you know
watching detailing cars
oh now you know how to do all these
things and then you can upload so we
didn't know that was a thing when
youtube first came around
but then we also i think there was a
shock factor like for for
you know our age our generation like
when suddenly you could start seeing
people you're like holy [__] like aren't
they gonna get in trouble like they're
posting a video of them with
weed weeds illegal you know like so it
was this weird thing we're like wait you
can
you can do that you know and that was
right you know after coming off the edge
of movies like jackass and stuff where
you're like wait
you can say that in a movie and you can
make money off it like you can do those
things
yeah and get paid for it whatever so is
i i feel like when youtube first came
around for
for our age and stuff it was just it was
this different thing
it was different i still remember the
interface that they had
and it was it definitely didn't look
like that it was very cheap looking
yeah well now they have they have t it's
like its own network you know youtube
premium tv or whatever yeah because like
uh now they have their own shows don't
they
yeah yeah like uh youtube originals yeah
which everyone has an original it's like
it's not really
original you i'm i'm pretty sure because
most of
your ideas came from a book or something
so is it really original or
did you yeah we're just overusing the
word original probably
yeah oh yeah like because they have the
the apple original
or apple tv they call it yeah apple tv
shows or whatever apple tv plus i think
whatever
but yeah netflix original blah blah blah
right because even like yeah even the
anime i watch
now they have like because i use
crunchyroll and funimation
but crunchyroll has crunchyroll original
i'm like
can we be original on that name yeah i
mean that's the thing about you know
running everything in our world through
capitalism is like this inevitable like
all right you have a thing you better
keep making it grow
you better keep making oh you got this
cool you know video app where people get
to upload videos well now you need to
make it its own network
yeah like that's how it is it's not a
bad thing that's how they make money now
it's like
yeah it's like oh how do we make more
money it's like yeah oh
we're we're reviewing everyone else's uh
content
how do we make money off our own content
but it's like are you saving money
because like
netflix did but then what a couple years
ago they're like saying like dude
we're losing money right right isn't
that real
right like i'm not making that up i'm
pretty sure a couple years ago
so they said they were like we're
actually losing money and like how
every household and even
culture i mean it's like you when
everyone knows what netflix
and chill is you would think that is the
most
like that company has billions and
billions of dollars
right you even saying netflix and chill
was probably a marketing strategy
like somebody at netflix i'm sure made
it into the meme culture
it populated yeah there actually there
was netflix and chill and then
when disney plus came out there was one
for disney oh was it
i'm trying to remember it disney in
his name oh i can't remember but people
are gonna look at i hope when they
listen and [__]
[Music]
they don't even cover it up yeah i
totally forgot what it was but it was
i laughed so like it was one of those
like nephews and chills like whatever
but when they came out with a disney one
and they had a saying and i
beyond me right now but it it's
hilarious so i'm sure somebody listening
right now is like yelling what it is
like i know what it is yeah i know what
it is yeah whatever yeah
dude it's crazy we didn't know when when
all these apps came out
like we had no idea what they would be
and i think even the developers the
people who made had these ideas and
stuff
they had no idea what they'd be now you
know even 10 years down the road down
the line
look we had no idea how they would
change us and then look at
just how often we're we're consuming
content now you know it used to be you
would just
go and you need something to do or you
know you need a tutorial you're like
i gotta fix my car you look up tutorial
for that specific thing but now it's
like
that's like where i get my information
for the day man
like i like i'm i listen to so much
youtube i'm on there all the time and
it's interesting to think that it was
just
one day uh it started out as just a
place for
any old person to upload a video and
then everybody gets over the years
everybody gets better cell phones which
have better cameras the cameras keep
improving
yeah and now everybody gets to be kind
of their own network
in a way you know yeah yeah that's
pretty
pretty true now i mean i think that's
why if you
really think about it it's like that's
how a lot of
companies or like those tutorials or
shows or whatever is like oh
shoot like we didn't know when we
gave these apps or
tools to use that
us common folk know how to use it and
like oh how are they getting
more content out there than we are
they're getting better than us like who
would have thought that this genius
right here
could have done it ten times better than
we could ever could
so now they're like oh okay well we'll
sponsor you
oh yeah yeah that's like hey no yeah no
we'll give you some money but
you got to do what we tell you to do and
how
what to say what to do and how to do it
like yeah you have a great idea but
we can we need money from you
yeah you know everybody wants their
chunk oh everybody
everybody does you know i most of these
like the
what what was that netflix documentary
um
uh the social dilemma oh yeah that was a
good one
i talked about this all the time on the
podcast listener if you have not
listened to the social dilemma on
netflix or listen to it watched it
you got to go watch it right now it's
[__] this podcast go watch the social
dilemma
yeah you know what don't listen to us
this is this was going to be a bad one
anyways
we're just going to talk about the past
this is a trash podcast
turn it off and go watch the social
media it's a good podcast but this
episode is going to suck
[Laughter]
so just stop what you're doing watch
social dilemma
on netflix and it will not change your
life
it'll just definitely change the way you
think and what you feel about social
media
when you when you first uh did you and
katie watch it together uh we
tried to watch it together but we watch
at a different pace
like uh when i watch something i can't
be doing something at the same time you
gotta be fully engaged fully engaged
i guess i like ever after taking my
medication now i can
actually kind of do that now but i
haven't really tested the waters yet
because usually when i'm watching
something and if i'm doing something
else i will
lose the last 10 minutes because i for
i'm forgetting i was
even watching it yeah and then i go back
but now
yeah whatever i've been paying attention
a lot more because of that
but we watch at a different pace
so we we really don't oh katie's calling
you oh she is
yeah you want to pause this yeah all
that pent up anger that i don't talk
about
which i need to fix but then it explodes
yep i'm that guy i
like yeah everything's cool that's why i
want to uh
i want to eventually get into like
brazilian jiu jitsu or something like
that like i want to get into something
where i can
like because i'm a i'm a very
i'm really like seldomly angry like i
don't i don't get angry that often
but uh like when i was younger i'd have
i could
get in fights and i would like black out
and like angrily fight people or
something you know
and so and like i feel like there is
anger or like
things inside of me that i could
healthily in a way
get out you know like yeah like whether
it's like you know mma
or like muay thai or brazilian jiu-jitsu
or boxing or whatever
kind of just a place that is made to
channel your aggression
out yeah and like hey here's a safe
place where you can just
let it all out like get it out on the
mat you know yeah i think that'd be i
need to find something like that
for sure because uh i've been i usually
not like take my anger out but i use
it all this pent-up anger that i use i
i heal myself by doing something i love
right and right now i i don't have time
i don't have time for that
and which is like it's not like oh you
can make the time it's like dude
i wake up i go to work we're about
10 lately for the last couple months
i've been working like 10 11 hours a day
yeah
i've been getting that um that overtime
for sure
and then i come home gotta eat dinner
but at the same time we're like we're
being feeding the kid
take care of the kid entertain the kid
and then after that it's
lifetime which usually lately i've been
kind of feeling bad because it's like
i haven't been giving her the time which
i should be
but it's like i don't even get myself
time so i'm just so tired i'm just like
i get stuck on my phone i'm like right
and put away your phone
say something to your wife
right right you know but she's on her
phone and it's like
and we're both tired you know you know
if that's that's something that like
i think we just kind of have to deal
with especially with kovid because it
you know coveted the lockdowns and just
all the changes in the last years
whatever like
it has sent us all down different
trajectories and it sent us all kind of
more
inside and more on our phones more on
our laptops more on our computers more
talking on zooms you know we're
our our hug with technology is bigger
now
oh like it just is yeah and it's
something that like
like you almost gotta like be gentle
with yourself in a way
in in and recognize like oh
like it's not just me like i'm not like
a bad person for being on my phone more
it's like
everybody's kind of going through this
we're all on our phone more and we just
got like now that we notice it we gotta
try to
to follow those intuitions of oh shoot
okay i'm on my phone a little bit too
much let's
let's put my phone down right now and
then i'm also gonna walk over to my wife
and say hey put that thing down you know
come here give me a hug
or whatever yeah you know talk or
something watch something together
you know we we we don't got to make i we
got to be careful to not make ourselves
feel guilty about it i feel like yeah
i mean some extent you know if you're
spending too much time you're not
getting your actual work done you're
just
sucked into your phone it gets so easy
it's literally like a [__] colorful
slot machine
in our hands man it's amazing like yeah
it's crazy but
we got to like insert you know
the ability to step out of it and and
notice okay
this is good this i could enjoy the rest
of my night just watching a couple
youtube videos and whatever
but i gotta put some time into here i
gotta put some time into the present
moment i gotta get some things done i
gotta hang out my wife i gotta
whatever it is you know yeah i think we
all gotta do that yeah for sure
because yeah i've been i've been stuck
on the
on the youtube thing man been because
i've been like
we were talking before i was i'm trying
to just
maintain my truck because so many miles
and body used you just got to do
it you know it's still running awesome
but got to do this maintenance
but so i've been doing that it's not
like i've been wasting my time or
anything
you know it's been oh how do i do this
myself or what do i need to do i'm
researching
if anything and it's it's been like
besides like car detailing thing i need
to stop that for sure
that car detailing thing is freaking
addictive to watch
i cannot stop watching that the before
and afters
dude i love those yeah it's the
the before and after whoever
invented that word good job
before and after like really think about
that
yeah that reveal do you ever watch the
um
like when they remodel houses and [__]
like they'll buy an old kind of beat up
house and they'll remodel it
yeah oh man when they show that before
and after like towards the end
and they show like the you know i swear
they add sparkles to it sometimes in
after effects
and it's like before you're like oh it's
not so bad and then you see the after it
looks like a whole new house but it's
from the same camera angle dude i live
that life man
yeah dude oh yeah i do that i we do that
every day well at least like just
electrically you know doing you know
being electrician and whatever so i see
that you know doing remodels and stuff
like
not so much the whole house you know
some sometimes we get like a whole house
but a lot of people are always it's
money money money
kind of thing so it's oh we'll just
you know put lipstick over it and that
kind of thing that's just because
they're trying to sell the house
whatever i get that
part but if you're about to live in
something and if you want to remodel a
house if you want to go full bore
it's like dude get it down to the bones
man get it down to the bones because you
have no idea
what you have it's like because
this russian kid he ended up not working
out for us
he actually he's the the kid that gave
us all coveted
besides like my father-in-law he was the
only one who didn't get him like the
oldest guy
is he the oldest he's the oldest one he
never got yeah i only had it for like 10
days but yeah
you had to quarantine though i had a
quarantine yeah i talked to you like
right around that time
yeah yeah yeah just so happened you text
me and i was like dude i can't do any i
got coveted yeah i was like
you were trying to like like katie and
the baby were uh you guys were all
living in the same house but you're
trying to like stay in the same room
right or like
into one room by yourself yeah i was
isolating yeah i i i had to isolate into
the spare room that we had that we never
used
like it was like my old bed that i had
like you know old queen bed that's just
been sitting there
it's like sitting there collecting dust
not literally we did clean it all the
time like
when we washed our covers we washed
those covers i'm like why are we doing
that no one
ever sleeps in there which i'm so glad
that katie has that mentality of being a
clean freak because
i had to stay in there that's the wife
hook up man yeah yeah
that's wifey material right there
telling me that i was wrong
to not clean it and wash it she's like
no
we have to keep it clean you never know
when a guest is coming over or when we
use it and guess what i had to use that
for
freaking 10 days it sucked but the thing
is i have no idea how
my daughter and katie never got it
yeah i woke up sick as hell
like it was i was fine the day before
like i had no
no symptoms nothing and i woke up
and i was like i had the flu for a few
days i was like
this is different i knew i knew it was
different and i was like what the heck
well around this time we're all also
like any time you feel at all different
yeah like
it's stupid is it i'm feeling sick you
cough a little bit and you're like
hey guys i don't have code just let me
know i'm good yeah
exactly right it's it's just a weird
feeling it's a weird time that we're
living in right now
but uh yeah i woke up and you know i
i really don't get sick when i do i get
like i'm sick yeah and so it was weird
to me i woke up i was like i
i do not feel good like my body
was aching and i had all the symptoms of
like
man this feels like i have the flu
but usually i it's like you know been
living for so long i know how my body
reacts to stuff
and i know the build up to things like
oh my throat's getting kind of scratchy
or
my nose kind of stuff you know i had
all of that overnight and this is like
like the week before we went to a party
like a birthday party but i guess it
takes about like
four days or something like that to
really have the to be
contagious and everything else was it
from the birthday party or from there no
it was it was from that russian kid that
we hired he was like pretty young he was
like
either 20 or 21 he was from
north carolina or something like that so
whatever and uh
he went to work after
visiting his family that came from north
carolina that's who he got it from we
found out
and he came to work he's like
and he like told us halfway through the
day
that we were all working together he's
like yeah i haven't been feeling good
like yesterday we're like are you
well and this was like if this was when
times were pretty high like
i feel like everybody's kind of relaxed
more on it now you know just as time was
gone yeah in this weird way yeah yeah
but this was when it was probably
if i think this was when it was very
because you i think you were one of the
first people that actually i knew
that had had it yeah dude that i you
know how many people told me that i'm
like yeah well because i had to tell
everyone at that birthday party
you know yeah i was like dude uh yeah
because it was two days before but i
guess it like
incubates or whatever and it takes about
four days to be contagious
and it was at the time that's what they
were telling me
so you know obviously the news and
whatever collect like collective
information about corona has always
changed right well at that time that's
what my doctor told me he's like yeah so
whoever you are with in the last two
days
because you probably got it uh two days
before that
but you were con you weren't contagious
so at the time that i went to the
birthday party it was
i wasn't contagious but i still had to
tell them
of course so i told one person because a
lot
at that birthday party i only knew like
really talk to like a couple people
so i i text my cousin i text one of my
really good friends
uh brandon uh barty oh yeah so i text
them like hey uh
i have coveted and so you should text
everyone
because i don't have any of their
numbers so they all had to go get tested
blah blah blah
and it was like me remembering who i
which
i'm glad that i don't really hang out
with a lot of people yeah
kind of thing i'm just not like okay i
really
i i'm just kind of guy that doesn't like
people so i don't really end up and make
a speech for the whole
yeah yeah so anyway so i woke up sick
and my daughter was right there right in
the middle
and katie right on the other side wow
woke up with it contagious everything
else
so i quarantined myself that that day
and i called in my k you know my
father-in-law is my boss so i was like
hey jack
can't come in today i feel really sick
i'm not feeling good
yeah and then this is that's when we all
found out blah blah blah
that like dude he that russian kid i
i think his name i can't remember he
only worked with us for like
a minute yeah maybe uh two months yeah
that's
vasily that was his name that is his
name sorry
and uh just dragging him through the
coals now yeah dude yeah
uh that guy i didn't really like that
guy but whatever
um he he's one of those one-uppers you
know
like oh you should do it this way blah
blah blah blah blah blah i was like dude
shut up you're barely an electrician
yeah okay time to learn bud
yeah it's time to for you to learn from
us not like what you used to do back in
north carolina but anyway so
so that was coming all into play so i
went out and i called
kaiser and i was like hey i need to get
tested just to make sure
and i was like maybe i'm just sick you
know maybe i'm just like whatever
it's i'll just go get tested
because it wasn't that bad yet you know
i was just like oh you know i don't
really feel good
got tested i got an answer because i
think it was like around 1 o'clock that
day the next
morning at 7 32 i remember this because
i was waiting on the answer and i was up
at like 6 30.
and i was quarantined i was in that
spare room already and i was
quarantining myself and we're like oh
no this would be bad because you know
our daughter's not even that old yet
i think she was i can't remember when it
happened but
i think she was only like five months
old or six months old at the time
and my test came back and they're like
and i'm looking and i'm like
this is some weird like thing to say
test results blah blah blah i'm like
looking at like what the heck
and right out the bottom it said
positive i was like
shoot yeah shoot shoot shoot
and then so we had to wait another four
or five days
and they went in on a friday friday
no so okay so i got it got the test
result tuesday
they went in on friday got tested
and uh they came up negative i was like
are you kidding
me yeah man my immune system sucks then
yeah or at least well that's what it's
hard to know yeah
i feel like all the answers around the
cobot stuff are so inconsistent it's so
confusing
yeah it's new yeah it's it's new and
then it's also it's ran
everything right now in america has ran
through political lenses for no reason
for no [__] reason yeah like
we solve complex problems but we've got
to make sure we run it through the red
and blue real quick
yeah and so it gets confusing but uh
yeah it's like it's hard to know
because it's hard to because i feel like
incredibly healthy people still get it
and sometimes incredibly healthy people
are people who take all their vitamins
and stuff they'll get it and they'll be
very sick
yeah and then people who you know drink
beer and eat cheeseburgers
every day seven days a week they'll get
it and they'll be like dude i kind of
had the sniffles for a day and i was
good yeah
so it's so it's so it's so crazy so what
do you think did you uh did you have any
of the
smell and taste loss yes stuff i think
that's the weirdest one right yeah
that's
weird i didn't get it i still haven't
had it to my knowledge so
so yeah that that whole thing sucked
yeah i wouldn't want to
it was it was super weird uh that time
um whenever that because it didn't
happen
right at first right uh it happened
after the fourth day because the other
the other days
like it was weird because i got super
sick
within those three days like i went from
kind of sick to
really sick and it wasn't my whole back
it was everything i felt to describe it
how i i felt it was everything around my
spine
it felt like someone was grabbing it and
poking knives into
the sides of my spine if i can describe
it like that wow yeah that's what it
felt like i
did not want to move i was super achy
but then
it was like once a symptom a day i was
getting
and it was because the first thing i got
was the back thing
i was hurting then i i was
i think the third day i was super
light-headed and i didn't want to eat
anything
which i did but i still could taste
right but i think it was her fourth or
fifth day
taste was immediately gone interesting
like i woke up and i went to go eat
breakfast
you know or not go eat breakfast my i
felt like i was
in jail and she would drop off the food
at the
at the front of the door and i would
have to grab
open the door and grab it and just go
back to bed and eat
there you know yeah and uh i went to go
eat whatever she made and
she makes these german pancakes right
and i don't think it was that day but
it was one of the days that she did make
no no okay we'll go back because i
wasn't that was later but she made
some sort of breakfast and i took one
bite and i was like
i tasted nothing oh right away you knew
right away i was like
wait what this is not what i because in
your mind because you can smell right
because i could still smell the time
because the smelling didn't happen until
the next day it
seriously is like when i have it it's
like new symptom you symptom use symptom
it was the weirdest feeling dude dude
it's such a weird thing
like i feel like everyone's onset
into covet is different everyone's like
symptoms are different everyone
like they happen in different times i
wonder if it really does have to do with
our individual immune systems or if it's
like something more complex than that
yeah i wonder i mean i'm sure we'll well
i'm sure we'll know you know in in five
years when we're looking back and we
have like actually
the right info yeah and we can actually
facilitate getting that right info to
the people's like oh this is what
actually happened and we figured it out
and this is why it
it got your smell and taste blah blah
and right
yeah because i it was funny because i
had it
not the shortest time out of everyone at
work because we
we were not work after that happened
every
like the whole place was shut down like
not like place i would have to say
because he
you know he doesn't have like an office
or whatever my father-in-law
jack but he all of us couldn't work
i didn't go back to work for until the
two weeks
because after whatever because as soon
as you have it you have like
two weeks but as soon as you start
feeling good and
as soon as like there's like a certain
mark in a certain
like once you have 90 percent of your
symptoms gone
i went back to work they're like yeah so
as soon as you you're not contagious
after that
everything else right so i i only had it
for like 10 days
i guess or i was only six six ten days
but i took
the extra not the extra but the two two
full weeks off
and i went back to work and i was fine i
i
never really got the heavy like hard
breathing part
yeah never got that i mean i got tired
when i was walking up the stairs but i
was breathing fine but
my body was tired yeah you know like
even after
yeah this is like after like i could
actually be with my daughter and walk
throughout the house because i was like
strictly from spare room
to bathroom spare room to bathroom you
know and it kind of sucked because
my wife had to wash her like you know
have
yeah take care of it well because our
shower like we only our
our main bath on on the upstairs
has a tub but that's the only place i
could go
so she had in our shower in the master
bedroom at the time
you know we were living there before we
sold it was the standing shower
yeah and so she's like it was the worst
trying to give her a bath poor thing
yeah yeah because like
even our kids kitchen sink downstairs
was
not that big so and she
at the time she was too big to sit in
there
and so yeah it was just i felt bad
because
katie had to work harder because like
she had to take care of the kid herself
which
i don't want to say that because there's
a lot of single moms you know but
it no she didn't realize how hard it was
until i was out of the picture
of course yeah i can change her i can be
with her i can take care of her so katie
can do something it was
full-time mommy duty right yeah i mean
i'm sure that was difficult as heck for
i mean difficult for you too because you
like you're aware of it it's not like
you're like oh cool i get a vacation i
ain't going to do anything and like now
you got to take care of it you're like
i'm sorry i wish i could help yeah i've
gotta i've got to do what's right right
now for the next 10 14 days or whatever
yeah so it's it's super strange i so i
to my knowledge i haven't had it unless
i've had it and been asymptomatic
um yeah i i feel that i've been around
enough just just like where i'm at
and like you know working in a package
sorting facility you know i feel like i
would definitely would have
would have caught it by now it seems
like that but uh i so i was in
i'm pretty good about um like a lot i do
a lot of breath work i do a lot of
breathing i'm working out a lot i'm
doing good running so i feel my lungs
and stuff for all pretty strong i take a
lot of
vitamins i take a lot of um you know i
feel like my immune system is pretty
strong
i shaylee my ex had gotten it at work
she had got it being a nurse and then
she went on a vacation or afterwards
before she knew
that she had it she uh went on a
vacation
and then they had sent her an email
basically saying like
sorry we didn't realize but you have
been exposed for the last three days
okay so someone basically had a false
positive or something like that
um and so i and i actually had taken her
i had taken her to the airport
when she had it she didn't know she had
it but it was like um
so she wasn't having any symptoms but i
feel like so so i'm not sure if it was
even transmittable at the time
but i was in a car with her you know we
left early in the morning so the windows
are up
like it was you know an hour yeah hour
there it's like that
like at the time that's your your person
so you're like dude you're
fine yeah yeah it's like you know being
anywhere it's like yeah i'm not going to
wear a mask around you you're like i'm
with you every day
right yeah no well we had broken up by
then anyway oh you guys came right at
the airport but oh okay
but she we it was interesting that
regardless even
that and then we i'm pretty sure i
stayed up there the night before
or something regardless it was i i
should have gotten it because she went
on
to the vacation and like the people who
are with her who didn't take vitamins
and stuff
they they got it they all yeah oh my god
this is how it happens
yeah but she didn't know it was like a
screwed up thing at work you know and
it's funny too because i i try to be
weary uh
blame myself when it comes to covet
because
it's this virus that it's like not it's
not any of our faults but like if you're
the person who
spreads it or you're the person who is
like
bringing it to other people it's
automatically like dude [__] you
you know and like she you know she was a
nurse so
it's obviously she wasn't she's just in
the in the line of fire
yeah so it just just could have happened
but um yeah so so i haven't gotten it um
i
i don't know i i'm pretty i'm kind of
like
overly cocky about it you know i wear my
mask i i do all the things you know i
wash my hands plenty and i
i try to play it safe and stuff but i i
just
i take all my vitamins and i do all my
breath work and stuff and
i hope for the best i don't know i don't
know if i'll get it i
it's interesting because it keeps
changing too you know the information
that they release or they're like
now that now they're they are saying
that it was from a lab in wuhan or
whatever yeah
and it's impossible it's i feel like at
this point when i hear information about
it i'm like
i don't know i don't even know if i care
to research it i don't know if i
it's just exhausting trying to keep up
with trying to follow all of the coveted
stuff
yeah it's almost just like i want to put
my head down i want to
you know i'll put my mask on i'm going
to go to grocery store i'm going to go
to work i'm going to do my thing
you know you just kind of gotta yeah got
to follow it
because i don't know when we're going to
it's it's hard to
to think of what the other side of this
whole cove lockdown
looks like you know like do you think
everybody's gonna get it eventually and
then once everybody has it and we have
oh like the flu like the regular flu
that we get every year
yeah i don't know i i
personally people are going to get mad
at me for saying this
and you know what i doesn't matter
because i
i'm never going to talk to you unless
you come to my house or
yeah whatever but it's
yeah i i this is to all the families
that have lost somebody
i feel for you i'm sorry you know but
it's you you gotta take in
everything else that's happening right
now too what people
are dying of and like
man this is this takes me back to the
conspiracy theory or
and even those and then actual real
facts that
i've seen you know whatever and the
percentages of people dying
i'm like uh it's like any other thing
like
why are we making such a big deal out of
this yeah because it's
very new yeah i get that and i got it
and i'm i got it and i'm still this way
so it's like
come on guys like yeah we are making a
big deal out of it
and i feel for those people that have
lost people i
really do but i feel bad for the people
i've lost in different situations
that's losing a person is losing a
person of course right
but to me i think this whole thing has
been
been blown out of proportion kind of
thing that's just my personal opinion
and uh i think it's been making people
crazy
it i've seen arguments happen over covid
i it almost happened at
where i'm living right now you know it's
about
where who we can hang out with i've
never been told
you know like who i can
and cannot hang out with you know it's
like why does that matter
yeah you know i i got a huge fight with
one of my family members because i
was i call it i was coveted scared
because for my daughter because two of
my cousins was coming from
uh colorado and they were coming for
thanksgiving and i'm like
and it got it got way blown i i haven't
been that angry
probably since like i don't know i'm
gonna
be comical about this probably since 99
yeah all right
i well now you got this father's wrath
in you
no because i was getting blamed for
something oh that's right yeah i was
like hey
you know like if those two kids are
gonna be there
you know they're i call them kids but
they're like 21 22.
somewhere around like maybe 20 i don't
know it's i haven't seen them in a while
but
they were going to be there i'm like i
don't want my daughter around that
and they're like i told my parents that
i'm like it's just not going to happen
but
you know we're probably not going to
have thanksgiving up there and that's
okay if you
like i never said don't bring him over
blah blah blah
and it that got blown out of proportion
then my other cousin that
text me saying you're you're such a
hypocrite blah blah blah like
what are you even talking about and
saying that i don't love you like this
is just an excuse
just because you don't like them like i
don't think i've ever said i
didn't like my our other family members
it sucks that you even have to be in
this argument though you know
it's something that wasn't really like
it's imposed on you
like like not that the virus has to be
like someone else's fault like another
person
to blame or whatever but it's like we
don't really know how to navigate these
waters like we don't know
like if dude if you're feeling genuine
genuinely kind of scared like
i don't want to risk my daughter's
health and i am actually concerned about
that
you should be able to talk about that
and say that you know
but but it's this new thing where you
know we're all kind of defensive about
it in a way right
where we're like oh you're you know
you're taking it out on me or you're
you're thinking you know calling you
calling you hypocrite hypocrite or
whatever yeah
it's really hard to remember that this
whole thing is not only new but it's
like we all
we're all dealing with so much
information none of us truly know what's
actually true
yeah so if someone's like ryan you're
overreacting or like you shouldn't care
about that
like they don't know what you've checked
out they don't know what you've
experienced like they don't know
like what you know news networks and
videos or social media
like videos or whatever that you've
watched that have told you certain
um aspects of certain information i was
watching this uh
i was watching uh tony robbins actually
who is someone
i i feel like you know this happens with
like influencers or you know
famous people or whatever like tony
robbins is someone at this point i've
consumed so much of his content
and if listeners if you don't know who
tony robbins is he's like a motivational
speaker he helps people a lot he's
incredible
but uh like i was listening to a video
and i've heard so many videos from him
that i trust what he has to say
like he just seems like a trustworthy
person yeah i feel like um
you know of course not every single
sentence out of his mouth i'm gonna
hang on to everything and say it's
happening it's just like your intuition
on like his
like characteristics and his like yeah
yeah he's a good guy
i trust what he's saying and i just
watched this video not too long ago um
that was saying
and it was him he was basically talking
about the numbers of like the death
rates he was kind of pointing out and
like this is
you know dipping into conspiracy theory
stuff and a lot of this information does
but he was basically saying
the amount of deaths per year
like based off like 2017 2018 2019 2020
they haven't technically gone up they've
been pretty plateaued like they've been
going as expected
but the reasons for death like flu has
gone down
like cold has gone down like all these
regular things that we experienced that
we normally
count as deaths those have gone down but
covet deaths now that they're marked as
coveted
replacing the new numbers
and so not more people have died but
we're doing all of this like locking
down the whole country shutting down
businesses like i i think i
i think i've heard 70 percent of
restaurants in la have now officially
closed their doors or something like
that yeah it's not insane
i heard about that dude new york is like
their crime is up like 50
like dude it's just like we're
we're as a country or like i don't know
if it's just because the news media or
social networks or because
we're listening to the wrong people who
don't know what the [__] they're talking
about anymore
we're reacting in disproportionately
like it just doesn't make sense like
if this is okay here's a factor here's a
percentage or here's a value like this
many people with kovid
have this or this many people have died
from covet how do you get from that
number
that we should do this like this many
people die from covid we need to shut
down
[__] everything and nobody can have a
single person inside their business
yeah uh you know for the next six months
or whatever yeah we're just reacting
very disproportionately
and i think the general public is
intelligent enough
to to recognize you guys what the hell
is going on like this isn't the way we
should be doing it we're watching our
luck like people we love we're watching
family owned businesses shut down we're
watching you know like like
people very stressed out we're watching
our you know people in our community
we're watching suffer
and we're suffering ourselves and our
family are suffering all this stuff so
i don't know it's it's one of those
things that's hard to talk about right
because it's like
you instantly are like man i think i'm a
conspiracy theorist you know
i'm not trying to go go against and say
everyone else is wrong
but there's also this place where we
don't even feel like we have a stage to
talk about what we really feel
because i feel like as citizens you know
just on like you know we're just a
couple regular dudes and
and we should be able to disagree with
what's going on without feeling like
confused about it or scared about it or
didn't hate it on
because it's like now that you have that
like canceled culture
it's like a culture yeah and then now
it's like if
like someone right now is listening to
this podcast this episode right now
and heard my opinion on it like
[__] that guy yep i can't believe he
believes that cancel this so i'm gonna
find out how he works i'm gonna call his
boss yeah and make sure he gets
in trouble yeah like i'm canceling him
like everyone should hate
ryan santos for saying yeah that covet
is
not as big of big of a deal than it
should be you know it's like you know
it's like
dude that's just my personal opinion can
i have one you've got to be able to have
one
yeah it's just like dude because i'm not
just when i listen to this covet stuff
i'm not just listening to
like my side of how like the numbers
thing and like
whatever it's i'm listening to both
sides
because it's like a lot of people don't
do that you're trying to decipher like
what's true
yeah yeah what is really true because
like a lot of people that have that like
really strong
covets bad blah blah blah and we need to
do this
as a as uh you know as a group we need
to get together and we need to
stop this covet and we need to follow
all the rules i'm like
dude the like and the p and those same
people
are i don't know if they're still going
out to restaurants or not and trying to
do
safety precautions because i never heard
i did a lot of research but i never
heard anything
when you're sitting at a restaurant that
this
the disinfecting part because they say
what like
once uh copied covet or like the virus
virus is on like because you can take
your mask off right because you can't
eat
with a mask on that's totally impossible
if you can without breathing in anything
that they've touched
and gave to you workers there all day
yeah and
people where you're sitting is where
another person just sat there
five minutes before with their masks off
yeah like come on can we explain that
because like oh no it's like you know we
have these tents up i'm like okay so
you're
closing in that tent so you're
basically almost in another structure
well
yeah you're you made outside an
inside yeah you can now eat but but
so this is the thing bro like
we all know that it's ridiculous like if
you go like if you go to a place where
they see you outside and you're like
eating or you go to a tap house you know
or whatever they're like we only have 25
seating but here you go here's this and
you and you literally talk to the
manager and you say like
hey do you truthfully believe that like
this is
going to stop covet if it's what we
believe it they're like no yeah i'm just
trying to [__] make money so i don't
so i can feed my kids yeah i'm trying to
make sure my business doesn't close down
we all think it's ridiculous yeah it no
it really is
like it sucks
it sucks because we are we are kind of
helpless in it you know in a sense but i
think what's going on
you know in in a a strange rebellious
positive light
i think that we could say you know
this time is it you know this is an
overused terminology but
um it's really woken up a lot of us two
two things about
it's woken us up to
how how we do things like instead of
just like the rat race of like we just
keep going and we just follow these
guidelines and whatever like
i don't think this dumb stuff this like
really
like this dorky way of doing things i
think we're all too smart for this now
man
i think that like we're you know we're
not all just sheep or whatever people
want to say yeah
i think that we're intelligent enough to
be like you know what we should be able
to run our businesses how we want to we
should be able to
open up our um you know open up our
restaurants
and like hey if we want to take the risk
we're going to take the risk
i think that i i think that instead of
just like following it and then like
you know not straying from the narrative
that's that's being told in the
mainstream
because we're afraid of the
repercussions we're afraid of getting
canceled we're afraid of getting
um in trouble or afraid of getting fined
all these things i think that we're
we have enough smart people now who are
kind of on this side of like dude you
know what this
this thing is [__] weird how we're
reacting to this this i don't think
we're doing the best
route i don't think that it's right
based off of the amount of people that
are actually sick
and the amount of like restaurants and
people who have lost their businesses
and are
you know maybe losing their home or you
know renters who are you know
like not getting paid any rent every
month all this stuff yeah because like
yeah that'd be like how do you
keep your like all the people that like
own
you know uh
uh why am i forgetting the name oh and a
part apartment complex yeah you know
oh my god i can't believe it's been so
long since i've been in an apartment
yeah it's an apartment
i haven't been it's been a while but um
they're
living in an apartment complex our own
apartment complexes it's like
the people can't make money but they're
still living there
but how does the the people that own it
making money
they are losing money every single
because they still got to pay
they got to pay for that land they got
to pay for the buildings it's not like
you know like i got to pay all those
taxes you know it's like everyone
everyone right now is losing money i'm
just glad i'm in
in construction i'm in a field
which is weird to me still
how we're s we've been the busiest i
the three years i only three years i've
been in construction working
this is the busiest time i've ever been
in
which is like weird to me it's just
because a lot of people are staying at
home right a lot of people a lot of the
people that have money they all they a
lot of people work it from home
now because of coven you know they
either they were forced to or
some people just work from home they're
just doing a lot of
reconstruction oh but to go back on that
uh
little sign up before we start talking
about that but what i was saying is like
about that restaurant part was um it's
like
do they have like that magic wipe
chemical to get does it just kill it
because if
that is happening this is a stupid
reason i i get it but like
if it's killing that how we how is it
that we're still all
getting it how is it still like so we
can go to restaurants breathe
all over the crap using someone else's
utensils by the way
right yes they disinfect and ever
whatever it's like it's so it's easily
killed
because they like they said from what i
heard from
uh i don't know a few months back once
the virus is on something
it lasts for a few hours yeah it is
something similar yeah so it's like but
you can just wipe it clean
and it just kills the virus i guess i
haven't done enough research on that
but still like what if
that cleaner wasn't good right
obviously they're gonna didn't kill the
hundred percent of it yeah
and like and people are still going to
restaurants all over the place
i mean that's why you got california
closed 70 of their restaurants new york
is just totally shut down
a lot of businesses are going out and
sad to hear but
it the whole thing i'm just so
frustrated because i don't know what to
think anymore
right that's the thing like how am i
supposed to think about this
like i definitely don't have the answer
yeah because it's like this has come
from an opinion from a person that
got coveted live through it
and what i'm saying is i i'm not saying
the symptoms were worse
i'm just saying i had symptoms i've
never had before you know like i've
when i got the flu when i when i said i
get when i get sick
which i really get sick i get really
sick i get the whole
achy body and like it just felt like i
had the flu
it wasn't any worse than when i got the
flu when i was
12 years old but that's just me yeah
and like i said i'm going to say this
again i feel for those who've lost
people i've heard
i've heard about it you see that yeah
it's like i
do feel bad and that sucks but
you know it's like like i said we're
blowing this out of proportion
and we're just people are just so
believing in what the media is saying
you know and that like the media to me
is uh mainstream media
what i'm saying is something i i really
don't want to watch because it's it's
i don't think many of us watch it
anymore like at this like yeah a lot of
our
younger generations we're pretty much at
the point where we're like we can't
watch it because it's so insane and it's
so ridiculous and it's so like
it's designed to attack your [__]
brain stem
so instantly you feel like you're in a
fear response oh yeah
people live in fear and that's what
we're right now we're
in the fight or flight mode right now
that's what everyone is and i which
makes us more at risk to get this thing
yeah puts our immune system at risk it
puts our entire system
yeah if anything this is what we should
do it's like the
my thing my dad used to make this joke
make him
like it's so bad it's not like it's not
like a really
a joke it's a thing that he just came up
with like when i was younger he's like
god people are such idiots you know i
was like i know it's like
people just don't have that that
the way their mind works which i'm
pretty sure is like talking about what i
was doing at the time it's like you just
need to be better than its people it's
like we just need to rip off all the
the warning labels off everything and
just
freaking let everyone just you know
natural selection happen
i was like oh my gosh but now that i'm
older i'm like
okay well if people are so scared they
should just go by that it's like okay
we're just going to stay inside
and we're just going to let everyone do
their thing and see
who's the warning labels yeah rip off
the coveted warning labels and
let natural selection happen i mean
and you know what yeah like people who
survive
you know what doesn't kill you makes you
stronger right
i mean you know that is as as a
philosopher kelly clarkson once said
yeah but uh but you know that's how our
immune systems work bro
yeah that's literally how humans work is
is we
you know if you have you seen bubble boy
remember that that movie
oh my gosh no one ever talks about that
it's dangerous
for him to go out into the world because
his mom protected him in this little
bubble
since such a young age with this like
fake fake he's like fake sick almost
basically
he just doesn't have an experienced
immune system
his you know in internal biological
systems have not been exposed to things
that teach them
and the incredible thing about humans is
we get taught from viruses
like like you catch a virus you catch a
cold you catch a whatever
when you're young and then you have the
antibodies you have the
your immune system is now built up to
protect it now yeah so
that's like the incredible cool thing
about humans yeah i
i i don't know if that's a good enough
blanket statement for
oh for kovid i don't know if that's like
you know build an immune system by
getting it you know it's not like
chicken pox or something
yeah i told you i feel like when the
term herd immunity first came around
um it was very again it was ran through
this political lens which is the dumbest
[__] way to run
logical thought through instantly for
some reason we take everything important
and we're like
and is it red or a blue idea is it
conservative or democrat or like
just it's just so stupid yeah it tells
the truth
yes what do you got back there talk
about what's really going on yeah yeah
like don't run it through these lenses
of how we should perceive things they
have so many mudding
yeah because they have so many plans to
try to fix this and
yeah it's been a year
almost a year now a little over a year
march
so to me march 14th was the day yeah
because i was working
i was working a big event actually up in
bellevue and we had like
man it was like two 2k high school
students
and and we're literally like we got
there and
with like we're setting up we get there
the day before and we're setting up this
whole event
and uh stage you know chairs everything
lights cameras
the whole that and um and then like as
we're setting up it starts we kind of
get like
trickles in some of the riggers are
starting to get emails like of people
canceling
their upcoming gigs and we're like oh
shoot and i had been watching the news
i'd been watching this thing from china
i'd been obsessively watching it oh yeah
everyone did
yeah yeah it was it was unhealthy dude i
was like literally before
before bed every night since like
january 2020
yeah i had basically started like like
every night would go to bed shaylee and
i and i would be like
this this this virus thing is weird and
i
think that it might be a bad thing yeah
and we're both kind of like yeah
because that was like i think yeah
because it was the first well they
mentioned they
supposedly was the first guy right yeah
that
like came over from i think from
china or came out from out of the
country into washington
you know what i think it was oh yeah was
it
i think he that guy was from bellevue or
something interesting of course yeah no
because it seemed like it seemed like it
was this very dangerous
when we were going to do the show they
were very debatable on like
we didn't know what it was they we
wasn't like like what we know about cove
and now and all the crazy repercussions
and all the lockdowns and the shutdowns
and everything
like that was not even a thought like we
never thought this is so abnormal
compared to how we have lived our life
for the last you know
30 years as a culture yeah you know it's
it was it was very weird
it's uh well it's just because they
talked about a lot once you hear media
talking about the one thing you're like
oh okay
and you keep hearing it keep hearing it
keep hearing it you're like
oh this must be serious right you know
it's like if there it's like
no one's talking about anything anymore
the one thing everyone's talking about
it's covered yep that's what our life's
been filled with and that's like
like you said it was like during that
time it's like man what's up
what's this coveted thing so why is it
such a big deal everyone's talking
that's
what all because i would like watch the
news and i
you know being uh hanging out with jack
all the time and working with him every
day
all he did did was like listen to
the radio stations you know and like i
haven't listened to the radio and soul
like actual stations
until him yeah a lot of older people
still listen to it oh yeah
that's all i listen to in the car now
yeah so i was like
[__] and yeah like you said it's like
i was like oh my gosh it was funny
because when that
happened i just so happened to buy
a ton of masks it was nice because i was
getting coveted scared
you know and it was like oh we're not
going to get this until
at the time we're not going to get into
until march
and so i ordered it like months before
and i everyone was out you couldn't get
it and i got it from
amazon and i got it right at march and
that's
yeah and then that's when the freaking
lockdown happened
wild yeah yeah it was crazy it's
interesting
noticing the changing tides of like how
we react to it
as it goes along you know like when i
because i started i started this podcast
last year and it's been over a year now
so it's been going for over a year
but i started it before covid and so
like
trying to after i had quite a good
amount of episodes in and then covet
hits and i'm like
i'm then trying to have this
conversation with people talking about
you know like talking about like their
dreams or their aspirations or their
like
you know being a creator or whatever and
i'm suddenly finding like i cannot get
out of
talking about covet where it's like yeah
we've been talking about cody for the
last like
30 minutes or something yeah but it's
it's our part of our reality it's yeah
you know
as much as i want to not talk about it i
think that
unfortunately and i know it sucks be in
in
listeners you know if if you're
indulging in a lot of news about covid
you've got to watch your mental health
you've got to
if it's getting to the point where
you're like scared walking around you're
constantly thinking about it
the people you're listening to aren't
helping you to like feel more safe and
at ease or
or understood even you've got almost
take a break from it like now literally
like coven news is something you have to
it's like you can't eat cheeseburgers
all day you also can't [__] listen to
people talk about the
deaths in covid and all this stuff all
day either yeah yeah i know
about it yeah we change yeah because it
grows
because obviously yeah it's like i'm
still taking the precaution precautions
you know
because we have we have to you know it's
like you can't go anywhere without
wearing a mask and i'm gonna obviously i
gotta you know follow the rules
to do whatever i want but it's just so
hard now
because now it's like you got to do all
these
you know procedures to go out right and
it's
to me it's so annoying that i got to do
all this stuff that i don't even want to
leave the house anymore
the only thing we ever do i'm like i
think well part
90 of it is because i'm we're trying to
save money
right now because we're building a house
and so like i
don't really want to go out and eat i
like i'm like get what we need
that's all yeah it's like we got to stop
eating out so much
like i'm like you know pinching pennies
here it's not like we don't have money
but
there's a lot of ideas in my head that i
want to do later for
our our new house you know but at the
same time like when going going out it's
just like a whole thing
you know it's like dude we got a kid
blah blah blah
it's like trying to get out to a
restaurant and it's like
everyone's not wearing masks like in my
head i have that duality
of uh oh i'm not scared of coping i got
it and i survived but then the other
one's like
[__] what if my daughter gets it yeah
her immune system
is not there yeah you know it's it's
just not there
yeah and it's like it has been like
we've been to
restaurants with her yeah do you find
yourself kind of like
i imagine you probably have like low
level anxiety every time oh every time
every time every time we take her to
like a grocery store or something like
that
and everyone's wearing masks the only
reason why we don't put a mask on her is
just because she rips it off every time
yeah and she starts so she's so easy and
she's so young and she
oh yeah she's not even one years old yet
and she's well one
she's not even a year old sorry i'm one
years old nah don't worry about that
sound like an idiot right there
but she's not even a year old yet and
it's like do i even take her out
do i freaking
leave her at home and just or do we not
go anywhere just buy our groceries
online blah blah blah
and then that's when i just get too deep
and like yeah covered scared i'm right
there i i you know and it's like oh
totally and like every time i just i
just gotta remember to breathe
and i'm like everything's gonna be okay
yeah everything's gonna work out the way
it should
and i think people need to start doing
that and i think
like i said it's been blown out of
proportion
and i think if anything we're just so
we're so
divided as a country right now that's
that's my personal opinion
we are so divided and we're not trying
to figure this out
together and the people the people
that know of kovid they say they don't
know government-wise scientists that
work for the government
they're just like yeah you just can't
figure it out i'm like well you figured
out how to
do a vaccine in nine months i think you
can figure out like what's really going
on
like if you found something to fight our
system or fight
the kobit to not attack our system
can you start like why are we getting
vaccines so soon
anything is possible at this point right
like how is this like
why are we why are you making a vaccine
where you still have to get a mask
and you still can get
covered but you don't show the symptoms
yeah it's like i thought um
sorry i would just want to don't
apologize yeah i get it
yeah these are things that we feel like
we're not allowed to talk about because
you know again there's there's cancel
culture there's all this disagreement
but
it's okay because i think that we're all
confused i think that you'll find that a
lot of people probably relate with what
you're saying i think a lot of people
probably are like dude i'm confused [__]
about this whole thing i don't know how
to react i don't know if i'm
overreacting i don't know if i'm
under-reacting
i don't know where to get the proper
news i don't know who's telling the
truth i don't know who's not telling the
truth
i what we should have done and this is
something that i will
i will say so many times and i still
think that it's important and i think
that's something anybody could do
um is what should have happened is at
the beginning
we should have basically had someone we
should have had a leader
someone who's a [__] grown-ass man
someone who is seriously
responsible and who is not caught up in
the maze or the illusion of the
the wwe world of [__] politics
yeah or or being a person at a podium
and a shirt and tie
somebody come out and basically say look
here's what we know
and they tell us what we what they know
like we you know it came from wuhan we
don't know right now at this point if it
came from a lab or not
when we know something that is
solidified that we can say yes it did we
will tell you
general public but right now what we
know is that there is a dangerous virus
that we as americans are going to
experience it's going to change our
lives
sorry but it is we're gonna go through
this americans
as an american like this person at the
podium as an american like
i'm telling you the truth we're gonna go
through some [__] our next year is gonna
be rough our next two years our next
whatever is gonna be rough we're gonna
work on a vaccine but in the meantime
what we need to do everyone needs to
work on their physical fitness
yeah everyone needs to strengthen their
immune system yeah here's the list of
vitamins that you should be taking every
day vitamin d
vitamin c zinc like whatever like oh you
know we should have had somebody at this
what i'm saying someone at a podium at
the beginning
of kovid should have said we don't know
we do not know
i'm going to be honest with you here's
what i think is going to happen but
instead we had like the lies about the
masks
don't wear masks do wear masks masks
don't work masks do work yeah
word two masks yeah yeah yeah we're
seventeen masses don't ever leave your
house
yeah exactly it's like we didn't have
our
our political system is the way in which
information is given to the people
and and i think we're realizing that's
not the best way anymore because we saw
what happened
we should have had a [__] we
should have like jocko willing i don't
know if you know that is but he's like a
navy seal guy who's like
he's yoked he wakes up at 4am every day
and works out and he's like one of the
most inspiring motivational
oh is it he's that guy where that
where's the beanie like super low or
something he starts yelling at the
camera
um probably that might be david goggins
oh okay yeah but
there's a lot of like really built guys
like just yelling the camera and that
makes me laugh i'm like where did this
guy come from they're bless them
yeah i'm like dude thank you for making
me laugh dude it's like
are you like this all the time like it's
probably that intense all the time
sir what do you want chocolate milkshake
right now
i need a number seven it's like i want
it and then he says like some
motivational thing
right after and then it's like drink
your milk and then that's it
yeah yeah
well no but dude this is okay this is
truly what i think like i
really generally think that at the
beginning that's what we should have had
we should have had somebody i i don't
give a [__] who it was
i think at the point when it happened
we're so untrusting of all of our
politicians especially you know
we want to in our hearts like what we've
learned so far
we want to trust we wanted to trust
donald trump because he was the
president at the time
what i i wish would have happened is
without all the [__] without all the
i'm this
you're that you're bad other i'm on this
side these people are liars falsies this
or whatever
all the crap all the fun and games that
we played in our reality tv show of
politics
i wish that someone came out and just
said like i said just
hey guys just lay it all out this is
gonna be rough and we're going to need
each other we're going to need
your we're all humans we have 300
million [__] people
in in in the us i think it's somewhere
around 300 million but like
it's time to come together because this
is going to be the hardest year of our
lives in the last you know
40 50 30 years whatever it is here's how
to take care of your immune systems
if you know something that we don't you
know get a hold of us let's work
together let's get our smartest people
on this let's get
this whatever but it turned into you
know all this
all this madness and we're still
confused it's a over a year later or you
know almost a year later
and we're still confused how to talk
about it what we're allowed to talk
about we're
nervous to talk about it like we're
literally like nervous to have an
opinion on it because we're
you know we don't want to get canceled
we don't want to get we don't want to
cause arguments
but we're all we're all just humans
experiencing a [__] virus
yeah and we need to be able to handle it
together it it's not what
you know when you take a look back in
his history
especially being an american a lot of
things that happen
anything bad and i'm talking about
throughout history like here
like somehow someway we always
came in together as a country
how did something this bad
divide us so hard and i'm not talking
just black lives matter i'm not talking
about
the left wing or right right wing during
the
president presidential election i'm not
talking about that kind of stuff right
now
i'm talking about a major event
let's take that into play let's take all
the times that
in history as
in america anything that bad happen we
came together
and overcame whatever how is this any
different
how how is this dividing us yeah because
right now
this is i think i mean
no matter what like some generations
like oh we went through the worst one we
went through the worst one you know
yeah but right now we're going through
another one mm-hmm
how is that how we're not coming
together how are we how are we
canceling people how are we being so
afraid to open up and talk about
our opinion even if it's right or wrong
because right now it's like i'm scared
to even say a word but now i'm saying it
all on podcast
now everyone can hear it but right it's
scary
it's scaring me it's like how am i
afraid to talk
because i feel like i right now it's
like freaking add up
you know add it up you're going to
cancel me i can't wait
because to ask me if i care because i'm
a nobody
but i have an opinion that probably
nobody likes
right now you know a lot of people don't
like maybe i'm
hopefully someone that is listening and
like feels the same way i do
but i'm not saying like oh let's get up
i'm like i'm saying like
i hope i'm not alone on this and it's
like
but it's hard to say like i said like i
have this
like i'm i'm half and half right now and
it's hard to say i'm not saying like
oh i'm just gonna sit here in the middle
and not have an opinion about it you
know it's like i have my opinions and
right now i just feel like
i've never been so confused on how to
live my life
until dude in this last year amen
that i i'm so lost like
it sucks i don't i don't even know how
to be myself
without offending anybody without
scaring anybody and
i i don't know yeah i it's hard
it's hard right now 100 i mean i i think
i i will say just from having because
i'm
i'm a pretty i'm i you know
i have my times of tiptoeing for sure
and i have my times i've all listened
back to old episodes where i'm like
i had i had one when the when the black
lives matter stuff first started
i had uh my friend mikayo who who's
who's black and i had him on and i
remember
like listening back is cringy it's like
i was so uncomfortable i was like trying
to tiptoe around i'm like hey
like how do i talk about this that's a
white person but i was almost like
i was almost like trying to talk to my
friend about this thing
from a place of from a place within me
that wasn't even my truth
like i i was denying my inner truth of
what i'm actually like it's like
wait i don't even like i don't i don't
think about like what racy is we don't
ever really talk about we're just homies
i don't know
like whatever like if he wants to talk
about it cool like let's talk about it
let's learn about each other whatever
but um watching myself tiptoe but it's
because all of these kind of like
self-editing tools that are imposed onto
us like our culture our media our news
all this stuff
it tells you that you should be nervous
to talk about these things it tells you
that you should
like make sure you don't say one wrong
thing because you're you're gonna get
canceled or whatever it is or you're
gonna get like
we're gonna find out where you work and
we're gonna make sure they fire you or
we're going to
uh you know uh come for you in this way
what i will say ryan is from me being
i'm fairly
i'm fairly exuberant about my opinions i
try to be
unafraid it's difficult honestly like i
like sometimes i'm like i don't know
what exactly i think but i try to
stumble through it on the podcast
the amount of messages that i get of
people with appreciation
saying i think that same thing i wasn't
able to even formulate it into words
until i heard you talk about it that way
and like honestly i just want to say i
totally agree and thank you for saying
what you're saying
like i get those messages and so i want
to say just as your friend
has someone who's having you on their
podcast like i i would be willing to bet
that more people are going to agree with
you than not because you haven't said
anything wrong you haven't said anything
arrogant yeah you're you're someone who
you're you're a new father who got
coveted you're someone who's experienced
kova you're
you're someone who's just trying to live
your life and trying to you know you're
trying to get into a new house you're
trying to
to to raise your family you know yeah
and you're suffering this just like all
these other people man we're all
brothers and sisters in this
yeah we're all suffering and we're all
taking this information from
you know the eric weinstein calls it the
gated institutional narrative
yeah and uh it's basically like this
this narrative of how things go and if
you step out of it it's like ooh
like that's not what we talk about like
yeah you might get ostracized
we're gonna we're gonna kick you out of
our tribe here if you if you talk in the
wrong way and
we gotta be not not afraid to talk about
it like like
we're all [__] going through this
cove thing the lockdowns the shutdowns
the craziness the politics
yeah the the crazy stories that they
make us fight about the things that they
put in front of us and they tell us that
are important or whatever
it's all adding up it's all the same
thing it's all something that we're all
dealing with and yeah
i think talking about it truthfully is
is legitimately helpful to me yeah you
should you should be able to
i mean yeah it just sucks you know we're
all going through
we're living yeah we're all going
through it and that's why i don't
understand like how we
how are we all not getting together and
figuring this out and like how to
better the situation at hand yeah but no
it's right now it's like
once you get that it just just so
happens you know
it was uh the election so it's like
right there boom
let's divide it people divide the people
mm-hmm and so
if you really do that yeah and then they
made the argument it's like
what are you gonna do about go but blah
blah blah and you know it's like oh
we're gonna do this oh we should do that
and it's like then you got these people
bashing you know it's like then you get
the riots and then you get
storm in the capital and it's like
what has happened it's so much has
happened within this year
it's insane to me i'm like this is a
time
we're living through well
kids in the future this is history right
now not like
the past few years yeah some stuff
happened
you know a lot of major things happened
you know but not like this
yeah you know this is the stuff that
kids are gonna read about
yep i hope we're all in agreeance of
that i hope
oh no they will okay i'm just saying
it's like if anything happens
if this like a whole collapse is
offensive to read about and then they're
gonna take it yeah yeah
2020 2021 we really don't talk about
that yeah
we don't talk it hurts a lot of people's
feelings yeah we can't talk about it
yeah
we just we had to burn the books just
like to kill a mockingbird we had to
take them off the shelf
yeah it's kind of like uh like it's one
of those things like you know you read
through the chapters
it's like people reading through history
about like the year 20
uh 2020 and then 2021 it's like
the elevator right you don't have
floor 13 right because we're
superstitious yeah exactly so
2020 and 2021 never happened we don't
talk about it yeah
someone brings it up people are like oh
yeah what are you talking about if i was
like no
no we talked about the future only that
was a bad idea for us you know what i
really do think though actually ryan i
think that
i think that looking back though you
know in a few years
i think a lot of the core of our problem
is technology
and and by technology i guess i mean um
uh
we've updated the way we do things so
fast in
the way our news works the way social
media works the way information gets
spread across like i've used this
example right now as you and i are
talking on this podcast i could facetime
someone in china
i could hit yes and suddenly we're
talking we basically have
a portal into being able to see
another part of the world yeah at this
exact moment
right like this little window called an
iphone and someone could like face their
camera at tokyo
yeah and i'm all sudden i'm looking at a
live stream of tokyo that's [__]
crazy
like for what human species have
experienced thus far
as far as we know this is the first time
we've ever experienced anything like
this
yeah we're the we're the ushers in of
all this
all this new technology and i think it's
so overwhelming i think the way we react
to it is overwhelming
i think that the people in charge the
people in shirts and ties the people at
podiums
um who are you know kind of supposed to
be our first line of defense on like how
to articulate and how to understand this
advanced technological communication
that we have now
they have no [__] idea what they're
doing hence why it's so confusing with
kovid yeah it's all divisive everyone's
scared everyone's blaming each other
we need intelligent people and i'm
hoping over these next couple years
young people i think young people like
i think young people are going to be in
leadership roles over our next like five
years or so
yeah um you know i don't have like a
bunch of facts to back this up this is
just you know maybe a thought experiment
or a prediction based off of
you know my own mind but i think young
people are going to be
stepping up in very heroic brave ways
and they're going to be the logical
thinkers i think they're going to be
like
look this technology we don't understand
it as well as we think we do
getting information like you know we're
talking about it just doesn't add up
that
these numbers mean we should shut down
all the businesses i think we're going
to learn that
we have all these facts we have all
these statistics
but the way we interpret them and say oh
this is this and so it means we should
do this
the way we interpret the facts yeah is
what needs to change
the way we process the information and
give it out to the people to the general
public the people who are not scientists
the people are not mathematicians
people who are not news reporters like
the way we process it will be changed so
i think on the i
i don't know if it's going to be super
soon to be honest i think we might have
like a little bit more time of some
some weirdness and you know i don't know
if the politics thing is over now that
trump's out or whatever
it's like that madness i don't know if
that's gonna calm down but
i think in in a few years maybe five
years we're gonna
we're gonna start having some smart
young new thinkers
standing at podiums or talking to people
through a microphone or through youtube
or
our virtual reality world whatever we
have at that point and it's gonna make a
little more sense i think that
as a species we're just overwhelmed and
we're confused at this whole thing and
we
we're going to have times we're gonna
have plenty of people who are going to
remind us that
hey we're all in this together man like
we're not it's
it's not us against us like it's it's us
against
the ability to process information
properly
and make the correct decisions to you
know give us all fulfilled life you know
it's so i i'm optimistic
i think in some aspects as much as this
is all crazy and ridiculous
and i don't know what's going to happen
tomorrow i do feel a sense of optimism
yeah me too i i hope so i mean
it'll be hard you know it's a lot of
people to convince
yeah it's a lot of people but
you know it could be us you never know
you know it's like how do you get to
that point like how do
how do you get to that point where
you're someone
is realizing how we're so sick
of the way things are going right now
for someone to have that one voice
you know and i'm not just saying just
when i say one voice i'm not saying
one person to have the voice
to try to change and get people together
and work with each other again you know
where was that
you know and it sucks because like when
i say
earlier about like america always has
gotten together
obviously there's things going on like
especially back then i mean you had
you know segregation and all that crap
and i understand that
you know i'm not just saying that i'm
not away from that yeah pulling this out
of my ass like i don't know about
history
you know it's just if you want to talk
about history let's talk about history
because i
watched that's the one thing that my dad
embedded into me was like dude if you
don't live in history
and this will always be embedded into my
head
which i will teach my daughter is if you
don't learn history
it will repeat itself and people a lot
of people nowadays
don't pay attention to that it's like oh
blah blah blah this happened and it's
like you know that already happened
it happened before yeah and and people
nowadays map for how this goes
yeah there it's yeah it's called
learning history yeah learning
not and it sucks because history it's a
little weird
because if you get into the school
history obviously the school books
they're only going to teach you what
they want to teach you that's what um
that's another subject but i'm gonna
paint you the picture they want you to
know exactly
so in the history that you learn
the winner writes history every single
time and that's that's what gets me huge
yeah it
it's uh so you got you got to learn you
can't just learn from school
it's okay to be that nerd
and going out and learning further than
what you're being taught
look at both sides of the spectrum yeah
you can't just look at one
and believe whatever you it's like
seeing is believing right
you can't just like read a book like oh
did you know this happened i'm like okay
were you there
did you go out and investigate did you
try to look for
the documents or whatever because
there's a whole thing because the
reason why that was written was because
people did that right right
over time collecting this uh information
and everything else
but it's like the what's that game of
the whisper game
where you like tell it oh yeah someone a
secret and then you
everyone tells that interesting you'll
be like the yellow
octopus jumped over the purple dog
yeah and then by the time it's you
whisper it in the ear
of you know five people by the time it
gets to that person it's like
the blue ostrich ate bananas
yeah what yeah you're like what that's
not at all what i said but just five
people
yeah it's just you know it's like
everything's just lost yeah it's
everything's like lost in translation
you know and uh
you know it's like you you think you
learn some things
but you're so far from it and that's and
that's what gets me
i that's like something weirdly i think
of every day
of like everything i know everything
i've ever learned
everything that i was ever taught how to
be
and doing the right thing
is it really right was i taught the
right way
some things that you can't trick
some things are exact like math numbers
no matter how you do math
yep you're going to get the same thing
there's an answer there's always an
answer right
but when you're talking about other situ
situations that we go through every day
where we're taught history
um the way to live relate like that
religion
what you believe like what you believe
in it that
confuses me every single day i don't
mean to yeah i i just
it's every morning i'm just like bro and
not sorry not every morning
but right before i go to bed i'm like
just sitting there i'm trying to listen
to music to block out the noise that i
have in my head
which is a voice and it's funny because
the voice i have in my head
is not me not saying i feel like i
have like weird personalities
or something yeah it's like i have like
a split personality but it's like
me thinking these thoughts of
like it goes to am i a good father my
good husband
and my good friend my good son
because i'm only going by what was
presented to me
at the time and i'm really appreciative
like how i grew up because
i didn't have i did have parents loving
very loving parents
that taught me the way they were raised
was it right to someone else no it's not
you know i take that in
sorry and uh
sometimes i feel like i'm like
a piece of [__] because i take
everything i have for granted
yeah and i try not to
like i just like try to block it out
and i hate that i get to that point
every night
because i work so hard try to
to be a good person
and i feel i i feel like i haven't
reached it yet
and i don't i don't understand like why
i have these thoughts in my head
it's not like i don't want to like kill
myself or anything
you know have those thoughts
but it gets to that point it's like how
do i change that
how do i um teach my daughter
the right things if i don't know right
yeah i get that what's right and wrong
how do i become a better dad
what's a good dad how do i become a
better husband
you only can see you're you're only
taught so much in this world
right and uh
it's hard yeah it's crap i think about
every night
i don't go to bed until like two i try
to
yeah just stay up trying to like think
about these things yeah just block out
the noise that's why i listen to
like try listen podcasts i try to
do whatever but i end up turning it off
and
trying to figure out like how
can i live a fulfilled life
without to blocking the noise
of every day yeah of everyone telling me
how to live life how to make life better
and because you don't know if it's right
you know
do i listen to you or do i listen to my
intuition or do i sorry about that i
didn't mean to
apologize buddy yeah it's weird do you
do you think that
do you think that you get down on
yourself like
like thinking you should know as
in like like why don't i have the
answers you know yeah i mean like it's
it's not so much that it's like man i
just feel
like every day i'm just unprepared um
you know i know my job i know how to do
that
that's a one two three thing yeah but
when it comes to
me like how i talk
how i act or react to
certain situations it's not
let's say i'm going to put this in like
electrical terms it's not up to code
to the way other people think you know
it's uh
it's hard i think it just has to do with
this like situation we're living in
right now it's
it's hard to express who you are without
offending anybody
and it's hard to um think
without being controlled
like like i said it's like it's it's
hard to
state your opinion without someone in
trying to bash it right
and it's like okay well i'm not gonna
act like that
but slowly and slowly over the last few
years i feel like i've just
just been losing myself
yeah and i don't mean you're trying to
figure out what's right yeah
it's weird because you think that you
should know this by now
most people you know it's like i get it
like most people don't find themselves
until
they have that weird oh i just
finally find myself out this is who i am
i'm going to stick to it blah blah blah
yeah yeah and i i thought i knew
until like i don't know like
a few months ago i wasn't like feeling
down or anything i was like having these
crazy
thoughts you know and i
and it's it's crazy to me to think that
i thought i knew who i was that i had my
figure in myself this is who i am this
is
this is gonna be me and hope everyone
knows about it
you know it's like i put this shell this
facade
over who over
somewhat over the real me you know it's
not like
it didn't have to do with who i married
she didn't like change me i feel like
i'm still it's like
things that i'm i think it's just been
comparing myself to people right where i
think i should be
and how i should act or
it i think that's huge right there yeah
and yeah it's just
it's just weird i i don't mean to have
these
thoughts but you know i'm only human
dude you're not alone in that that's
what i'm saying like i really feel like
you're not alone in that yeah
i think a lot of people are going
through this right now like yeah dude
like what do i do like
how do i raise my kid good like i don't
want to yeah
you know like cool my parents love me
but now that i see
where you know i would have probably
done differently like how do i make that
an actual reality
like how do i really do that yeah how do
i like what information do i tell
my daughter like what who do i tell her
to trust because right now i don't trust
any of our institutions i don't trust
any of our
you know there's so much craziness going
on there's so much um
you know new complicated ways of
thinking and stuff it makes sense to
always be
to be you know trying to find out like
am i doing this right
yeah and i think ryan because you're
such a you're such a caring and sweet
person that you
inevitably even if it wasn't your family
and of course your family adds
tenfold to it yeah you want to do things
right man like like you
you want to do the right thing you've
since i've always known you like you
you want to do the right thing you you
want to make people feel good
and you want to be yourself too yeah but
like sometimes if you're editing
yourself and you're like
like is this the right thing to say like
like i'm not trying to hurt anybody's
feelings like i
i think that like i we're talking about
earlier i know you
so whatever you're saying i know your
intent yeah like you were saying you're
listening to our first episode like a
year ago
yeah like and you're wondering like oh i
said the wrong thing right
i i didn't explain myself uh how i
wanted to or how i thought i was or
whatever but
since i know you i know your intent like
i'm here i'm
able to look you in the eye and i know
you know like we can almost finish each
other's sentences in a sense because
like
i understand what you're communicating
deep down but i think that sometimes
and especially nowadays in this in this
world the words themselves
are what we get caught up on the words
themselves are like tripwires
and and that's where we get nervous
about like oh i i want to say the right
thing i want to do the right thing but
i think that what the true humanness
within all of us
the way that we really communicate with
each other is intentionality
yeah and and it's like you you want to
with all of your actions with the way
that you teach your daughter with the
way that you speak to your wife with the
way that you talk to your coworkers with
the way that you interact with your boss
like underlying that because i know you
you're trying to do the right thing
in all of those situations yeah but the
world is so complicated right now the
world is so weird right now the world's
so
so messy and when i say the world i
guess let's say the way that we see the
world because of
the lens that's painted for us in
america let's say yeah but
the intentionality is not always
communicated so i don't know i
i think that something something good to
remember
and try to try to remember is like
like going back to yourself like
sometimes i think ryan would get caught
up with
like other people's voices and we
mistake them for our own
like you know there's always a part part
within us me especially like you know i
meet me too i i'm always trying to like
how can i do better like how can i
how can i be more how can i improve
myself how can i be jake 2.0 in that
situation how could i
oh i [__] up like how can i make sure
i never [__] up again yeah you know
that's a good thing but we also have to
be gentle with ourselves
because i think deep down you got to
remember to like remind yourself like
dude i'm [__] i'm doing my best
i'm doing my best i'm doing my best not
i'm not doing arnold schwarzenegger's
best because his best honestly might be
better than mine and that's okay
yeah he's not in my shoes he's not
living my life you know
i think we're all we're all trying to
operate
with the life that we've been handed
we're trying to to
teach others around us and teach our
family members teach our daughters teach
our
whatever it is yeah based off of what we
learned
from our parents and what we learned
from our community our our
you know our uh lived experience around
us
but also like our intuition our inner
feelings yeah so i think
i think it's like it's it's so hard man
but like we got to try to remember to be
[__] kind to ourselves and like
really really be able to like
like do do you think right now and and i
i
i mean i i like correct me if i'm wrong
but i feel like you could probably like
if
if you looked in the mirror right now
and you looked in your eyes and you said
like
hey i'm i'm doing my best yeah could you
could you believe that like
do do you do you feel like like you're
and not your best like
i could be doing more but like really
truly like
like you knowing you don't have all the
answers you're not a magical being
you know you're you're a human with
flaws and emotions
and experiences like i'd be willing to
bet ryan that you're
you're doing the best you can right yeah
i i can honestly say that i
if i look in the mirror i'm like dude i
work my ass off
you know yeah you do i you know
sometimes i'm just
like uh
consciously not there like i'd say
sometimes because i
just been working so hard lately it's
like it's super busy right now you know
but it's like
i come home say hi to my daughter
say hi to my wife you know and
sometimes i'm just so disconnected it's
just because like i'm just like at the
end of the day i'm just like oh my gosh
tired right right but like i'm like hey
you know what i'm
doing this for us you know it's like
sometimes i just want to unplug
for a bit but that's not
i can't do that though i try not i try
not to but i i just do it because like
i'm physically
tired you know i'm up down ladders um
all day you know and just like trying to
wire these houses and
like so i'm physically moving carrying
things
yeah for about 10 11 hours a day when
you're a fast thinker too so your
brain's also working yeah exactly
and you have to because it's like time
is money you know like in that industry
it's like dude if you don't do this
we're like and he sets the schedule out
if we're longer
if we're there longer than we're
supposed to we just lost money yeah you
know so time is money so i'm like i'm
constantly thinking i'm constantly doing
math measurements and everything else so
by the time i get home i just
you know like i tired yeah i'm freaking
tired yeah dude i don't even have time
for my
dude i can't remember that like the last
time
i said that weird remember the last time
i
sat down and played video games like i
think it was like maybe a month ago
i played for like a i think a couple
hours or like uh
maybe a little night or thing but i
think that's the last time i play i
don't
like play like like everyone knows that
like every time a new system comes out
i got it i'm buying it this is the first
year i never got like the new ps5 or
something or
xbox whatever yeah i'm like dude i don't
have time for that
you know what i have time for some
learning how to
like update my truck all right and or
watching detailing videos at night and
this is like one o'clock in the morning
just doing your best yeah so i'm doing
my best but you know it's like
it's not so much uh that i
i i um
i feel like i'm so down on myself i i
feel i feel like i can do more
not just for my family you know i feel
like i can
i see people who are struggling because
i can't be
you know like when i was emotional about
that i just like i just want to help out
people that's like my intention to be a
good
how do i become all these things and
also
help and make people aware of what's
going on and helping them out because
right now it's like
why am i complaining when people are
struggling
so hard and i have money right now
building a house
a brand new house in these times yeah
yeah okay i mean it's not like you're
like a millionaire and you're [__]
like oh i've got my jet flying in my
magic bricks to build my mansion house
with the pool it's not like that it's
like you're just
you're lit you're trying to live your
life and maintain building a family and
a home for your family bro
there's nothing you should feel guilty
about at all i i i
i think i think i'd be willing to bet
that more people would relate with
exactly what you're [__] going
through
like the pressure we put on ourselves
yeah and the pressure that
like someone who just cares about other
people and cares about of course your
family like your family is going to be
first and foremost like i care about you
most like like
i i want to be good for you i want to i
want to do my best for you
i want to learn what i can so i can
teach you
whatever it is but then there's also you
know you also got to deal with the facts
that you're a biological creature who
gets tired man and that's okay
like you you work all day and you use
your brain all day you know uh
chess chess masters like they've been
known to uh
burn six thousand calories during a
chest mass like a grandmaster chess
player
real six thousand calories from sitting
there thinking
that hard really you can burn from
thinking
apparently yeah i mean that's probably
why i'm so somebody check me on that but
i'm pretty sure yeah i've i've heard
about this i
was just listening to it not that long
ago but that has to be why i'm well dude
it really is it really is 100 a thing
when you're using your brain that's
it's it's tiring you know and also
another thing here
you haven't been doing this for that
long like like you know you're [__] now
with electrician
yeah but as it gets longer as it's more
years it's not going to be as draining
for you i i don't imagine
no it's getting to the point where it's
like it's getting pretty easy
but that's just because i've been um you
know
taking my medication been taking my
adderall you know
so thinking has gone skyrocketed
yeah like when i get on the one yeah the
focus
to to be able to focus and not stand
because like
people at work used to make fun of me
because i would be standing in the
middle of a room
looking at what i'm doing and just not
doing anything
and they were like dude what are you
doing i'm like
thinking and i totally forgot what i was
thinking about
and i'm like well and but i bet you if
they never walked into that room you
wouldn't have thought
you wouldn't have forgot what you were
thinking about yeah if they would have
left you alone you probably would have
yeah resumed where you needed to go well
yeah because
my biggest thing is i couldn't multitask
that was my biggest thing it's getting
it's getting a lot better
i mean it's still like you know you just
see remnants of it
right but after you know being on the
medication what since uh i want to say
december
i want to say november december is when
i started it dude it's
i don't do that anymore i don't stand
around in a room
i i already know what i'm doing because
in my head
because when now i will think about what
i'm doing
and then um instead of standing there
and thinking about what i need this
where goes their their power switch leg
blah blah blah
it's me doing that while i'm doing
whatever i'm doing and i'm like thinking
about the next steps i'm like okay this
goes there blah blah blah
when i was standing there i was routing
everything i was doing
you're walking through it yeah i was
walking through it and that's what i
i didn't get in trouble but it was like
it was a stern hey
get moving i said yeah hold on i i i'm
trying to plan this you're like i'm
working yeah yeah i mean dude that's the
thing we're talking about before this of
just
the the difference in the way that
people think like they're we're all just
very different people
you know it's i i have uh i think you
were saying something similar like you
like your doctor might have been
explaining it in some way but when i had
gone in when i talked to my doctor about
um adhd and adderall
um he was kind of explaining to me
in in similar ways of like you know
it's not that like there's something
wrong with you it's not that it's not
that
the way that you think is broken it's
not that the way you think is like some
sort of death sentence it's like
when you have adhd when you have like
your the
focused center point pilot of your
decision making
doesn't always have the ability to
choose the right
importance but then but then and that's
just one aspect of it and then another
aspect
sometimes whereas someone else would
just do something and figure it out
along the way
yeah sometimes it takes like all right i
need 10 minutes to draw this out in my
head because i don't even fully
conceptualize
how this works and if it doesn't work so
so for me
this might connect for me
i have trouble focusing on things that
i'm not interested in
and that's like a weird no right like
that's it's
like i feel like i'm saying i'm lazy
basically when i say that
but it's it's it's untrue like so in
that situation where you're
trying to wire up a house yeah you're
not going to have as
much interest in doing all right here's
my step one
step one i need to go to this socket
right here and i'm gonna start with
these wires that's step one and that's
gonna
create the whole electrical circuit
around the house
uh correct me if i'm wrong but if if i
was in that situation
and i didn't fully understand the whole
the big picture
if i didn't know what i was doing like
how does this one socket that i'm doing
affect the whole electricity of the
building and what i'm actually doing
like what my job is
i would not only not fully understand
how to stay focused on this one task
because i'd be
perplexed on how i'm seeing the bigger
picture but i would also
not be very interested in this task yeah
like it wouldn't be interesting for me
to do because
in my brain i'm not able to organize it
into the
this is important folder and so i think
a lot of times people with adhd
they have um maybe maybe an inability in
comparison to other people
to prioritize what they would say is
important so we almost have to draw the
picture in a completely different way
yeah so you're saying where other people
would probably walk in the room and they
just start with this thing and then when
they get to the next one they're going
to do it
you've got to stand in that [__] room
and visualize it you've got to
see what you're doing you've got to
build like okay what does the puzzle
really look like
now i'm going to pick up the pieces and
now i'm going to start
putting it together yeah yeah that's
it's kind of like that
you know it's like and
to add to that when i'm doing that
when i was just standing there thinking
it would be uh because there's always
more than one way to wire something that
was the thing
and it got caught in my head i'm like i
could either do this
i could do that or this and
it's funny to me because uh my
father-in-law he would be like
ryan there's three ways to do something
choose the right one and it's like you
have to like because he's been doing it
for like 35
36 years or something like that so he
knows
when he wires our house he knows when he
comes back on trim
to do whatever he knows exactly where he
put the wire
he's like i wire i wire the same thing
their houses they're easy it's one two
three deal
which i know in my head now for you know
just doing it three years
and that's how i think exactly like him
now
i'm like okay well when i walked in the
house this where i would put it
blah blah blah this is where i put a
homer blah blah
this is how you do it because if you
keep doing the same way
you will never screw up later and you
will know every time where the power is
coming from
where you put the switch leg and how you
wired it right yeah
now i'm i'm at that level but before i
wasn't
and so i was like dude i i can't get i
don't
understand what you're doing especially
like i've i wasn't in construction
before i was a dust guy i was a salesman
i
went to i drove in a car wore
some nice shirts so i can sell something
to you that you probably didn't want
anyways
you know and i never did like
i don't get them in that microfiber
black shirt bro yeah dude
you have to it always looks better dude
once you upgrade you can never go back
yeah so
um it was that it's like it was a
different
way of thinking and i wasn't used to
that especially fast-paced
i was i'm like when i thought something
through i love to think about it
for a long time and think about it you
know just like i like
details mm-hmm what what really like
where did this stem from how does it
work
i like that i like the slow pace this
job
no yeah that is how to go out the window
you better know what you're doing in and
out because like i said before
time is money which is a lot of jobs
you know but it's like can you think
fast enough and that wasn't me i
couldn't because i would think about
every single possibility
on how to do something i'm like dude you
can't just go with one because you got
this one
this one this one what's the easiest way
mine
because i'm dude i'm lazy i am probably
the laziest person
that you will probably meet and i'm not
saying that i think you're redefining
the word lazy here though yeah
exactly but it's not saying that i
sit on the couch all day and not do take
care of my kid or whatever
not clean up i'm a very clean person
everything's done
yeah but how how am i going to do that
step
faster than i was going to before and
still
have an effective way to do it it's
another way of saying like what's
what's basically what's the best way to
do this oh yeah in a sense
yeah it's like yeah yeah dude like i
said i'm the laziest person you'll
probably ever meet
but i'm gonna get the job done yeah and
probably better than it was before
i think it was it was either steve jobs
or steve wozniak uh who said
uh uh it was like i'd rather hire the
lazy person
um because they know how to get the job
done faster or they know the the
shortcuts to getting the job done
something like that i'm totally
butchering it i'm sure but um
it is i think but but i think our
culture calls it lazy
or or it's misconstrued for like what
are you doing dude like why
just pick up the tools and get going but
we all just think differently so you
have learned how to
like like now you're like a pretty
skilled electrician you've learned how
to do this craft
like you had to sacrifice some of the
ways that you typically think i imagine
but you you kind of have combined the
way that you think as like a
uh you know you're a specific person who
thinks only a
one one peculiar way you've combined
some of that with thinking kind of like
what other people would call the right
way yeah like this is how you get the
job done
you know so it's a i think a lot of
people
a lot of people go through that i think
a lot of people try to i i
you know i always try to say learn how
you learn that that's one of the most
important things you can do
because if you are sitting in a
classroom and you happen to realize that
you're the only one out of 30
30 other students that like doesn't seem
to be
focusing or paying attention or learning
the other things that other people
learning
it doesn't mean you're dumb it just
means like you maybe you haven't learned
the way that you learn
maybe you need to um pace the room as
you learn
maybe you need to be listening to um you
know
maybe instead of sitting there and
reading a solid book maybe you're
an audiobook type of person yeah and you
like to walk around and listen to it
listen to that book in your headphones
that's
best way to get it so exactly i think
that i think that you're like learning
you're you're learning how to you know
be true to yourself and be true to your
authentic
and in peculiar and creative way
of thinking like the the real essence of
of who you are
yeah and accompany that with you know do
doing the right thing and make sure you
properly do the job like yeah exactly
do the damn thing yeah exactly you just
like you know there's
like i said there's like or like my
father-in-law says there's three ways to
do something
choose the right one you know but make
it work
make it work for you yeah and do it the
right way you know it's like
but you have to have that will yeah you
have to want to become better
it's not like when i got emotional
earlier it's not like the fact that like
i
just i'm just done it's the fact that i
know i can do more
right i know i can better myself yeah
it's just like you know that emotional
because you're hard on yourself
i am you want to be yeah
and so it's like i tell like some of the
people that i see
it's like dude how are you not doing
that like
why do you not want more are you just
like if you're comfortable for
being like doing nothing all day
i mean that's lazy when i see how you
live
the way you act i'm not like trying to
judge him but it's like
dude you have skills that you don't even
know about
it's like and i know that or
like i said it's like if you want if
this makes you happy
this is it for you and you've reached
your highest point
and this is all you want to do then
freaking do it but do it the best that
you can
you know but and also yeah if you know
if you are doing that thing and you are
doing the lazy version yeah but you know
every day
that like i could be doing better i
could be doing a little bit better and
you ignore that yeah
it's not going to feel good that's not
how humans work man yeah it's like we've
got to
you've got to be able to you know you've
got to be able to balance like that
feeling of
and it's not [__] easy by any means
you got to balance that feeling of like
you know i'm doing okay all things
considered you know it's been pretty
crazy lately
but i'm doing my best you gotta be able
to balance that with
i gotta do better oh i gotta keep
improving you know because
the i've gotta keep improving puts you
innately in a place of
i'm not good enough yeah and so that's
like yeah a place like that i
like stem from and i'm trying to like
block that out like yeah and i
need to reflect i'm like hey you're
doing
better than a lot of people are doing
bro in the world and like a lot of
people that i see like
people i know it's like struggling i'm
like you know like i
do then i start you know it's like
almost like a reminder that i'm like
dude i'm doing
awesome yeah you know it's just like a
little thing it's like when you see
things it's like
that's when i like i feel bad i'm like
what the heck ryan
why were you in that like state of mind
when you're seeing this situation
at hand you're fine you need to stop
doing that you know like but i'm still
hard on myself i still want to become
better and i'm like and i just want to
sometimes i just like want to motivate
people because people some people are
just like
you know i'm fine like you s you know
you're sitting here i was like i'm fine
you know i could be better but they
don't do anything about it
you know or they're stuck in a situation
but they're not willing to do the work
you know it's it's i would have to say
everything i experienced in my life and
how i
changed over the years and what how i
became
who i am today to change to become
better
with the mindset i've always had the i
always made excuses
to like oh i'll do that later or you
know i don't know it's because my adhd
or
whatever being lazy kind of like that
like i was lazy back then but now it's
like
i'm lazy because you know i find a
better way to do it in a short amount of
time
by doing it the right way yeah but now
it's like
i've changed so much
that like i i couldn't believe i lived
that way
and me growing the man i've become today
i just don't understand how people can't
do that and
which i finally did it's because the
like i connected i connected it to what
my dad told me
a long time ago and i was young and i
never understood like
you would tell me things that like weird
things
little lines i still remember to this
day
that wisdom that like yeah that wisdom
it's like man
like dad you're weird you know it's like
why would you tell me that like i have
no idea what you're doing
it's stuck and the line is he told me
he's like
ryan when you want to do anything
and it's like when you want to become
better
when you want to do something that your
heart desires
it doesn't matter if you're capable or
not it's
the hardest part of doing what you want
to do
is taking the first step because if you
never take that first step
you're never going to do it that's it is
the simplest line i've ever heard in my
life but
it got me to be more i guess
more courageous over the years after i
figured out what that line meant
and it's like man it's like it can go
stem from asking a girl out
to trying something new
or you know eating something new that
you never tried before
to making the move for from me
going from uh from
longview all the way down to vancouver
for this girl to move that was the
biggest step i've ever
taken in my life was to move down to
vancouver not knowing anybody but her
you know it it's to sing what you want
to say
what you want to do at work you're never
trying to lose weight or something
you're never gonna do it
unless you take the first step and that
is the first step
you know when you're learning how to
walk for crying out loud what's the
hardest step
the first one that stuck out like as
soon as i figured out what he meant
when i got he i think he told me when i
was like nine or ten
i was so i was like whatever dude you're
crazy but now that i
like i think i remember that line when i
was like
in my early twenties that really stuck
out
that taught me everything that like got
me
to actually talk more be more
personable to be more taking
courageous steps that no one would ever
take i'm like you know
try things out you know it's right
you're never gonna experience life
unless you
do it yourself yeah you know you're
never gonna figure things out you're
never gonna do anything with your life
if you don't take that step dude i uh my
friend bob bob kendall
he he said this thing way long ago when
i was uh
i was working at munition actually i was
probably like also working at mr formal
but yeah
he said uh you can't win the lottery if
you don't buy a lottery ticket
and it was just someone just said that
the other day yeah man it
has always stuck with me in that same
sense and it really is you know it's
it's just
you know i was as you were telling me
like you know take that first step i was
just thinking
[__] nike man like nike just do it
you know so slogan we all here three
words
yeah just do it it really is like just
just do it you know the same thing yoda
said
you know there's there is no try you
know you just you
you do or you don't you do so it's it's
it really is
those things can stick with us in
profound ways and isn't that cool to
think of like
bro like think about how many things
you're going to
give your daughter that you don't
realize you're going to give her yeah
like
like you could be giving her some casual
advice that you don't even think she'll
remember but then
in 20 years she might be with her friend
on a podcast being like man
my dad said this thing and it's always
stuck with me
and you know i hope so it's probably
just going to be like dirty jokes or
something he's like
dude my dad is just super gross he is
[__] inappropriate all the time
it's like you think he would have just
these simple dad jokes but they're just
weird and gross i feel like okay in 20
years what kind of dad do you think
you'll be you think you'll be like a
dorky dad
maybe oh dude i feel like you'll be
dorking oh i'll be a super
dorky nerdy like my dad
watches air max's model yeah mow the
lawn and then he's like dude my dad
watches anime
like that's weird i don't i don't get it
i'm like
yeah you'll get it once you learn that
leveling up and
in a show is the most crucial thing and
you get excited
and you get off your chair and you stand
up on the couch you're like let's
go
yeah i don't know why i still watch
anime but i love a lot of people watch
anime yeah it is
it's actually grown up grown so much
since i've started
it used to be like this like stigma of
like oh you watch anime that's
gross like but now it dude it's uh weird
people do or something yeah it's like a
nerdy cosplay blah blah blah that's not
how i think i just like dude the story
line's too good
it's the storyline yeah yeah you're
listening to a story be communicated you
know that's that's what entertainment is
for us is we're listening to
again like we were talking about uh
towards the beginning or even on that
first clip we were talking about
basically
like as we're speaking it's not always
about just the words
it's not always just about the median
it's about the message
it's about the underlying theme like
what what are we communicating my my
friend texted me yesterday
and uh it was friday night and i know
him i think he might have been having a
couple drinks yeah
he texts me um and he basically was
was uh you know saying like hey man you
know i want to hang out we haven't been
able to link up for the last couple
weeks like i really miss you i love you
and then he and then he was um we sent a
couple messages back and forth and he
was like
you know you're my rock man like i
appreciate you i'm kind of going through
some stuff right now
um you know just he was basically just
like communicating his appreciation
and it's just totally you know you know
bro lovey moment and i text him back i
love you too buddy whatever
and based off of the words that he was
saying just through a text message
like like like you could take it a
different way like i i i you could take
it
if someone else read those words and
they don't know either of us or we don't
know like the the friendship that we
have together
yeah um they might be like like what are
you guys talking about you're just like
saying you love each other
through the message yeah but what i
heard i didn't
looking through the words that he sent
me themself looking through that
to my friend communicating with me what
i heard was
my buddy's having kind of a rough day he
just kind of wants to hear that he's
loved
yeah that's what i heard yeah 100 so i'm
like i get that and i hear you and i
love you brother
like entertainment does that for us a
lot of the times yeah
that was my connection back but i know
yeah like
a lot of times we're trying to learn a
message about life we're trying to learn
about ourselves we're trying to learn
about
again you're watching anime like you're
inadvertently learning how to be a
better father as you're watching these
things you're like
how do i what's the story here what's
the human lesson here that i'm learning
from the theme of this show
like that's dude all these things
you know we don't ever talk about it on
this level we talk about on the surface
level like oh did you like that show no
it was good
it was bad or it was dumb or i didn't
like the music or the acting was bad or
whatever and it's like [__] all that man
like what the story listen to the story
yeah yeah the theme that's speaking to
our heart
you know oh yeah that's i don't know
that i
that's why i watch anime dude they just
they're
to me they they tell a story
and everything is like you know
obviously it's like all seasons right
it's like
sometimes they have like it's one season
where it's only like maybe
12 to 24. sometimes they just make so
much right
but there's some that they make like
like there's one that i'm watching and
it's like i'm on
episode like a hundred and fifty six oh
my god yeah
in one piece no dude that was a long one
too
no yeah i think they're in the thousands
right now oh my god that's so many
episodes yeah
like i i think how creative that is
though it is the creators and the the
animators and the writers behind it like
that's
crazy yeah but then it's like some
people like so mistakenly like make fun
of it
and i'm like okay and then they turn
around it's like okay let's go watch uh
frozen
a girl that can freeze uh
freeze it literally has magic and can
freeze things and talk to a goddamn
snowman
that she created with magic that's okay
but your anime is childish
it's childish yeah i was like okay
so we're going that oh no because it's
disney it's different i'm like
still animation man it's still different
and
guess what disney is a multi
what i want to say billions yeah they
have to they they own espn
they're a part of like what hulu is
connected to them now because
like yeah fox yeah dude it's all there
they own everything they own me
yeah they own you oh yeah plus they own
my car i don't think i own my car i
think disney owns it yeah you know how
many times i watch tangled
oh dude you probably watched a lot uh
tangle's like one
of actually that's a top five for me
actually yeah tangled i
dude wait till your daughter gets older
too you're gonna be watching these
way more often too dude that freaking ah
every time the song comes up
okay i would have to say like uh like
the newer no i'm not talking about old
disney
i'm talking about new disney now it
would have to be like tangled
it's like one of my favorites it's a
really good one i every time the first
song comes on kitty would always laugh
at me because i know every word
yeah i'll sing it out loud uh frozen two
actually i thought was better than the
first one there's some see
i like the music i thought was better
i've seen
two the two is really good yeah it's
like there's a part where the
guy sings in there and obviously i know
every word
and uh he uh don't tempt me i'll do
right now oh dude
but um he sings but like the the way
like the way the song is it's like
um they weren't making fun of it but it
was a well yeah it kind of make fun of
parody
but it was like like an 80s a weird 80s
like look on like or in his situation it
was like an 80s music video
like a really soft and like he's
speaking his heart out kind of thing but
it was definitely like the way they did
it was like 80s okay like late 70s
early 80s like the way they did it and i
laughed so hard that i loved the song
it made me love this song and i
memorized it i was like dude and then
katie
everything i've learned because she
watches a lot of disney uh movies
i stopped after like the 90s because
like
like that's all the best movie like dude
goofy movie oh that was like
dude that was a good movie oh my gosh
dude all i wanted to do
is become powerline like i know i don't
as a kid when i was i was like dude
i would i still from this day i when
katie puts it on
for me because she knew that was my
favorite i i can read
or i can say all the words i can it's in
there
it's i know every single line i know all
the songs
it doesn't matter i can i can literally
just recite the whole movie for you
i love that movie so much till it's like
that's the song that you played when we
walked out on our wedding
was uh it is dude yeah
dude goofy movie was one of those
underrated
movies i i feel like because not a lot
of people know the songs
i guess i don't know i just i connected
to that movie as a kid so much
yes so good can i just say i'm gonna
completely
change the subject can i just say that
the fact that you had a band at your
wedding was so dope
like shout out to bands oh um yes
yeah like i i was i was a dj
like i don't want a dj at the no
i i don't know like i i don't know i
mean i don't i i've did quite a few
weddings and they're
just not my like favorite thing to do
you know they're great
they're great money it's great to be a
part of it um but i
i don't know there's just something
about a band man i found myself dancing
way more with
isn't it weird yeah you feel like you're
more connected right yeah i didn't
think so much i did not think that
having a band there
because in my head when i think about a
band i was thinking about a bar they
were just a play
like playing in the background yeah
there's playing in the background
they're just playing old music
oh man we were all dancing our butts off
yeah because it's like they're playing
the songs
that when we all get drunk at the bar
yeah
those are the songs we're dancing to and
we're
yelling on top of our lungs when they
put like a funk vibe to everything
yeah you know everybody think everything
had a solid baseline the drums were
hitting you know like in in the the
singing
had a great voice too and yeah yeah
because the singer
and then the girl like or the singer is
has a twin sister
and she can play the guitar and she can
play drums or something like that
yeah but like they're twins and they
both can sing but though
at our wedding it was mostly the one
girl that sang and the other one was
like i think playing drums and every now
and again
i think she was playing like the base or
something like that something was
happening i can't remember it was
a lot of things were happening in that
wedding but i just remember watching the
band
like at a bar and i was like oh okay and
i'm still like whatever
but when they were playing and everyone
was on the dance floor when i was trying
to dance
my best because of when i
um i uh my achilles
i ruptured my achilles injury yeah right
before
the chair yeah yeah i almost fell by the
way don't i try not to think about it i
was like
holy crap you guys this is i didn't know
this was a jewish
wedding yeah we had the bar mitzvah that
[__] uh yeah it carried me
and i i was holding on to dear life
by the way i'd scared the [__] out of me
oh man i was like dude if i fall that's
a re-injury right there i'm just getting
healed up
i already feel bad i was wearing a boot
yeah at our wedding but i was like dude
things happen
yeah i think that it has to be yeah you
gotta roll with things man but
you're right dude having a band i will
tell you this right now whoever
still made it this far after our whole
coven
to my emotional cry to
finally talking about some funny stuff
but
having a band and not a dj not saying
anything about you
jake [__] djs yeah i would have to i
would recommend
hiring a really good band that can play
every because they played every type of
music
and the way they played it was perfect
because it wasn't like
yeah very upbeat and they kept the i
don't know they just kept the momentum
where it's not like you're standing
there watching a concert
it was the hey they're playing music
that we can dance to and we don't give a
[__] about the band but they're just
playing music
yeah that we would like to do it was
every song
from it was they played 70s 80s 90s
music now i mean because i know they
played funk you up
and i'm like dude you guys killed it are
you kidding me
yeah and they i mean it's like a band
playing that
yeah you're not you're not going to get
that i mean i guess groovy too
oh it was it was like every cover they
did was just good too like i think i
would enjoy like even if it wasn't you
know my good friend's wedding i think i
would have just
i'd really enjoy even if i was at a
place where i was just kind of having a
beer listening to them where it wasn't
like a dance place
i would totally enjoy that yeah because
like the place that we saw them because
you know like
well from here you know i
i guess i was like accustomed to where
when you're just listening to
a bar band you're not gonna go out there
and dance
you're just gonna listen to them right
right when i first saw
that band when uh katie's parents were
talking about like oh we should get a
band i'm like i don't know
that'd be kind of cool i guess i don't
know i never really saw like a band
where you can just get grooved to
whatever but i saw them live
and i kid you not when like we were
waiting for them
to play right it was like billy blues in
vancouver
that's where they played at that's where
we saw them and they were regulars there
that play and you know that you got the
people it's like
like an older crowd too and people would
be dancing and stuff
but as soon as that band came on because
they look like they're around
my age or maybe a little bit older yeah
i think the twins are like my age but
when they came on there was not
one seat that was still
like a butt was sitting there oh
everybody i'm telling you i
everyone came up out of their seats and
started it was
did their job i've never seen a whole
bar get up
and just start dancing like and they're
they weren't just playing like old music
like i said they were playing new music
now and i'm telling you like people my
parents age
were seeing singing because they played
[__] you up yeah and
uh i was like dude why this old guy
like like he had to be like maybe 57
56 in his late 50s he sang out
every freaking word i was like what
is happening right now i was like okay i
get it
i want them at our wedding let's book
them yeah book book them and
like you saw at our wedding man every
everyone's out of their seat
great time yeah it was good that you
know and you never
i've been a lot of weddings like a lot
and a lot of people don't dance
yeah you know unless they're super drunk
and they're the guy that
walks out to the dance floor with a wine
bottle in their hand
trying to grind up on somebody not
talking about myself in the past cutting
shirt more
i takes off i'm not talking about myself
but at our wedding dude i don't know i
just had a really good time it was like
one of the best weddings not like to
brag
yeah but dude that was a good wedding
that was having a great time
that was yeah that was a good do you
remember the name of the band like
did they have a no but i'll send you the
tag or
i'll text you like the what the band was
called because i know i know i just
figured shout them out you know
now bands aren't working nowadays isn't
that crazy like all the bands all the
people who used to play anybody who
works in the gig industry
has not been doing anything they've been
trying to do the rest of it
yeah you know that sucks dude but if you
actually if you go i think if you go to
billy blues
there they have a website for that bar
and they usually have a lot they
used to have a i don't know about now
but they had the lineup and like the
dates people are playing and stuff like
that
um if you go look on there if you
search the bands and if you see two
twins singing and they have
it's weird because on the website you
see a video of them playing
like a show there and it's like not just
like a recording of one spot and you're
just seeing them play
it's like uh like someone made this
video to look like a video yeah i was
like what the heck
that's what you gotta do today yeah like
you have to yeah because they
they're really good i mean i i watched
them actually after our wedding i
watched them
play and they were playing for free um
which you know obviously they would play
for free unless you book them um
they were playing at the casino
they played for like uh two and a half
hours at the casino
and yet again watching those people out
there on the like everyone out
at the dance floor i was like you guys
are are you here for the band or
i'm here for gambling and i ended up
watching them for an hour
yep that's that's how i was like oh damn
it dude i love letting your ear catch
you
and then it's like yeah we're just gonna
check like who the heck are these guys
yeah well because
yeah they're really good singers the
twins are yeah
yeah well it was enjoyable i i enjoyed
your wedding i enjoyed the band
man i feel like uh if there ever comes a
time in my life where i get married i
don't know that i'll get married we'll
see but
well i think i'm different i told myself
that dj but i
know you can't really plan it right like
right now obviously it doesn't fit into
my life even
halfway right now so it's just
just not gonna work out in that way for
me but oh remember when i told you about
that meme earlier
i was gonna tell you about what katie
told or sent me
was that uh
you know you're doing good when you're
uh when your husband from fifth like for
15 years used to be the
the the high school druggie and now
is downstairs cooking eggs for your
daughter
and she sent me that and i was like damn
that was really harsh but that is so
freaking true because the other that
because the other day
uh she i let katie sleep in and i woke
up because
baby woke up got her out and she loves
eggs and i was cooking her dinner
you know or cooking her uh breakfast and
uh you know i was making her she loves
eggs and
getting some eggs made some french toast
for her she just like you know cutting
up
cutting them up and then yesterday and
that was like a couple weeks ago and she
sent me that yesterday and just made me
laugh i'm like
we laugh and then maybe a little like
that hurt a little bit damn but yeah
yeah
i used to be the jury okay i get it you
know i'm now i'm
always i barely drink this is probably
the most beers i've drank in a long time
actually oh yeah i'm sure yeah we were
just talking about like is it yeah just
how life goes man yeah we've had plenty
of beers together when we were young but
yes we did i mean we had a lot more
together it becomes a more special
special
time thing and yeah like now we get a i
don't know
it makes things more of a special
occasion it's it's fun it's nice
i enjoy it oh i every time i you
give me a text i i light up and then
she's like
okay she's like who are you texting why
are you smiling like
it's jake it's jake it's jake he's
texting me
be on a podcast bye bye i gotta go bye
gotta go gonna be on a podcast okay i
get it right yeah can i get it right
yeah
um uh okay dude it's uh
we're getting pretty up here in time and
the old wifey will be here to pick you
up shortly
yeah so uh firstly i just want to say i
appreciate you buddy thank you so much
for coming over it was great to catch up
it's just great talking yeah it's always
i appreciate you
uh you know being willing to be
vulnerable and like just talk about real
[__] too
yeah i can't wait for people to see me
cry
because i was actually gonna say during
the podcast i'm like dude ever since i
took my medication i haven't like
been emotional and i was like dude it
like cut off my
emotional thing but for some reason when
i talked about that thing
because i think well sparked it yeah it
just yeah because
i don't talk about that kind of stuff
and i don't know why i talked about it
now yeah we just we
we kept leading yeah i did it just oh
man i didn't mean
like once i when i get with you i
freaking talk about things i don't
i don't even talk about my wife i'm just
like dude i'm solid man
yeah emotions what is that yeah
and then yeah that just like came out
and i guess that was like just pent up
emotion that built up
well i'm i'm glad you were able to let
it out as a normal human man i'm glad
you're
the only current part of my my guy in a
safe spot
yeah oh i'm always in a safe safe spot
with you dude oh good man
glad to hear that i feel safe with you
too buddy thanks i appreciate you so
thank you for doing this
and let's end with one last question
given the choice ooh to fight
100 normal-sized bats
or one giant
horse-sized bat oh dude always go for
the hard one
that's uh i would go i would think
the horse size back can still fly too by
the way yeah exactly dude if
anything um it's from an anime
actually and this old guy in the anime
always said
when i play video games i always turn it
up
to the hardest level you know why in the
whatever he was talking to this kid and
this whole situation happening and he's
like
it's because that's how life is
there's no easy mode in life and that's
how i treat every every situation
i play in hard mode and i was like
holy crap dude that hit me on so many
levels so
everything i do now life is a game from
that you know i will always be
fighting a giant horse bat
yeah all right you're going to go for a
size bat yeah
i would that's the heart i'm going yeah
oh i'm going oh man
yeah i feel like a horse-sized bat would
whoop your ass right honestly i
probably would eat me for sure but you
know i would have your back i think the
two of us together i think we could take
out a horse-sized bat oh i'm sure the
fact that he flies like
hopefully it's not nighttime because
then he's really got one up on us and
he's using like
[__] sonic sound waves too i mean
well it all depends on like
what kind of bat is it like a fruit bat
like the ones that only eat fruit i mean
i don't know just because he eats fruit
but it like maybe he's harmless because
he eats fruit but if he's [__] huge
maybe he's suddenly like maybe his or is
it the one that changes
yeah or or is it the one
do you want to pick the one that like
actually
licks or eats blood because what it does
it turns into dracula
yeah but there's a type of bad that
actually flies around
and um goes to horses or uh
any type of animal big animal they do a
little slit that where
the animal doesn't know and they
actually drink the blood of that animal
that's crazy there's a bat like that i'm
pretty i don't know i'm really into
when i was a kid i was into discovering
reading books of
animals and i know more than you should
know about animals and
the names of them and i can't remember
for some reason i can't i used to know
that one because that's stuck on there
like that's
super freaking gross and yeah and that's
where actually that's where
the whole turn not the whole turning the
vampire thing but like a little bit of
that
was because that bat was into that story
of vampires and
everything yeah interesting yeah well
hopefully the bat that you have to fight
is not one of the blood-sucking ones
just a fruit one because it is if it is
then it's not really hard mode after
that
because all you have to do is throw a
giant fruit
or a bucket of like avocados like here
you go
you just assume that the bat is going to
be completely ignoring you because you
throw some apples
uh here you go and then after that we're
best friends it's not even a fight mode
anymore it's
um i just i have a best friend a new one
and it's a
size bat yeah
do you think katie would approve if you
brought home a pet horse-sized bat
i don't think so well we'll see we'll
we'll catch this one like it purrs a
little bit
it's like kind of like a cat but it can
fly yeah it's like a giant
mouse with wings and by giant i mean
it's the size of a horse
yeah don't worry wife give him a name
before you introduce him to katie
because then when she has her name you
know she's going to be like what you're
like what you're really going to
you're going to make me just leave henry
outside
henry henry paul you're going to leave
henry paul
just outside henry paul the bat yeah
oh my gosh that'd be so that now i'm
thinking about that that's the most
ridiculous thing
i've ever thought of i never thought of
a situation where a horse
sized bat ever in my life now you have
now it's something you got to deal with
and if it ever comes up in your real
life or in virtual reality world when we
get there yeah you're going to be like
well [__]
i might have to get like a tattoo of
that horse-sized bat
it's got to be across your whole back
though it's got to be your entire back
and how am i supposed to represent that
it is like a horse size
you got to put a banana next to it
that's actual regular-sized banana
so i have to do a comparison first of
all have you ever seen a banana
next to a horse
all right man i appreciate you we'll
leave it on that note
okay listeners take care of yourselves
much love to y'all remember that you're
human remember that you
go through this same whole crazy thing
as everybody else we're all brothers and
sisters through this
yes we're all we're all in the madness
of everything that's going on right now
we're all in it together so remember to
be compassionate remember to be kind
remember to be nice to yourself be
gentle to yourself
and uh we're all going to get through
whatever we're going through
together sounds good that's awesome exit
yeah
peace out much love
[Music]
knowledge is power